<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Default on </title>
    <link>https://dragarok.github.io/tags/default/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Default on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dragarok.github.io/tags/default/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dream of Himalayan Yogis</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2025/05/dream-of-himalayan-yogis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2025/05/dream-of-himalayan-yogis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dream-of-liberation-from-fear-to-truth&#34;&gt;The Dream of Liberation: From Fear to Truth&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The wise ones teach that the universe was born from the desire of The One—not out of pity, not to cause pain, but from a longing to multiply and know itself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the Chhandogya Upanishad (6.2.1) declares,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“sadeva somyedamagra āsīdekamevādvitīyam&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;taddhaika āhurasadevedamagra&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;āsīdekamevādvitīyaṃ tasmādasataḥ sajjāyata”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—“Somya, before this world was manifest there was only existence, one without a second. On this subject, some maintain that before this world was manifest there was only non-existence, one without a second. Out of that non-existence, existence emerged.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 in a nutshell</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2024/12/2024-in-a-nutshell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2024/12/2024-in-a-nutshell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started this year differently compared to years before. In the year&amp;rsquo;s end, I saw who I could become, who I was and got some glimpse into what 2024 was going to be about. Really got energized already at the start.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2023 was speeding with insights. Its been a slow year compared to 2023 because everything was about calming down. We built a home for ourselves. I realized having a home that you design and build yourself based on how you want it to look like and make you feel, is a great blessing. Its been one wholesome journey to build my home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Vipassana Experience</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2017/10/my-first-vipassana-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2017/10/my-first-vipassana-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The journey of it starts with a recommendation from two of my friends. I, being desperate to experience something spiritual and majestic, decided to take on a 10 day Vipasana course.&#xA;Being an Engineering student from tech related field, it&amp;rsquo;s quiet essential for you to cope through the old dying syllabus and find yourself some life through the Internet. The rapid outbursts in Physics and Technology like the Neural Networks,researches on the quantum field with startling papers like &amp;ldquo;Universe shouldn&amp;rsquo;t exist&amp;rdquo; made my mind wander a lot beyond my control.&#xA;It was as if knowledge was on a different level trying to exploit the unconscious parts of the universal intellect as well as mine. Having read a lot but pretty much experienced nothing in particular as per I read, it was one of the reasons to give a fair try. But mostly I wanted a piece of my mind to recognize my deep interests among the disruptive tech bubbles in a 10 days self-exploration. Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to move.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
