<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://dragarok.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dragarok.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Smiling like a madman</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2025/06/smiling-like-a-madman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2025/06/smiling-like-a-madman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First I was innocent,&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;I asked for an identity,&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;The world pushed me down and pained me.&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;I talked to the world about this pain,&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;And the world mocked me.&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;I felt alone in this fight,&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;I wanted to run away.&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;But, she didn&#39;t let me.&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;She made me break into a thousand pieces,&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;But always took great care that none was lost.&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;And when I gave up,&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;She made me work on myself.&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;And That&#39;s how I recollected myself to be wholler than the whole.&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;-------------------------------xx-------------------------------&#xA;&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;Second I was in limelight,&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;I asked for strength,&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;Then the eyes of the world fixated at me pained me.&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;Their dreams, their expectations,&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;Them trying to fulfill their dreams through me.&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;I again talked to the world about the burden of expectations,&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;And the world really didn&#39;t care.&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I felt alone again in this fight,&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;I wanted to run away.&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;But, she didn&#39;t let me.&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;She made me take even more burden until I broke again,&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;Yet she took great care again that none was lost.&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;And when I gave up,&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;She made me work on myself.&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;And That&#39;s how I recollected myself to be wholler than the whole again.&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;-------------------------------xx-------------------------------&#xA;&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Third, I was now strong enough to take any burden.&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;I asked for truth,&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;I started wandering here and there in search of truth,&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;The words from thousand masters buzzed like a bomb inside my head.&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;But by now, I knew the world never listened.&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;So I chose a few I was hoping would listen without judgement,&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;Tried telling them about the never ending search,&lt;/br&gt;&#xA;Yet they too didn&amp;rsquo;t get much.&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dream of Himalayan Yogis</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2025/05/dream-of-himalayan-yogis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2025/05/dream-of-himalayan-yogis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dream-of-liberation-from-fear-to-truth&#34;&gt;The Dream of Liberation: From Fear to Truth&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The wise ones teach that the universe was born from the desire of The One—not out of pity, not to cause pain, but from a longing to multiply and know itself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the Chhandogya Upanishad (6.2.1) declares,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“sadeva somyedamagra āsīdekamevādvitīyam&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;taddhaika āhurasadevedamagra&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;āsīdekamevādvitīyaṃ tasmādasataḥ sajjāyata”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—“Somya, before this world was manifest there was only existence, one without a second. On this subject, some maintain that before this world was manifest there was only non-existence, one without a second. Out of that non-existence, existence emerged.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 in a nutshell</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2024/12/2024-in-a-nutshell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2024/12/2024-in-a-nutshell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started this year differently compared to years before. In the year&amp;rsquo;s end, I saw who I could become, who I was and got some glimpse into what 2024 was going to be about. Really got energized already at the start.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2023 was speeding with insights. Its been a slow year compared to 2023 because everything was about calming down. We built a home for ourselves. I realized having a home that you design and build yourself based on how you want it to look like and make you feel, is a great blessing. Its been one wholesome journey to build my home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 14:49:33 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;alok-regmi&#34;&gt;Alok Regmi&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am a Software Engineer with Bachelors in Electronics and Communication&#xA;Engineering from IOE Pulchowk Campus, Nepal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Curiosity is my prime interest.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ML/AI is my primary work/passion.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Currently working as ML/AI Architect.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Problem Solving is my core skill.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m intrigued by anything and everything that even remotely concerns human&#xA;mind. The more complex an idea is, the greater the interest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I love to read as much as I can. Intention of my writing is to find conflicts in&#xA;the content I absorb from all my musings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Love</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2023/10/on-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2023/10/on-love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been trying to write some essays on basic words that are the hardest to capture because often times it&amp;rsquo;s these words that stir up conflict: love, happiness, fulfillment, peace, pain, god,  spirituality etc.&#xA;Because they are the most overused, yet least understood by our subconscious minds, our subconscious gets trippy while making sense.&#xA;I started writing this essay about six months ago.  In trying to write this essay, I started by searching for word love in my personal notes vault. It got overwhelming even after a day digesting, that I gave up the pursuit for some time. I really didn&amp;rsquo;t have any digest apart from notes and excerpts from others. I knew where to start, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t end it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turning a quarter old</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2023/09/turning-a-quarter-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 17:05:00 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2023/09/turning-a-quarter-old/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;books-read-this-year&#34;&gt;Books read this year&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Brave New World&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;One Hundred Years of Solitude&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Twilight Saga [ 1-4 ]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How to Read a Book&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What would you do if you weren&amp;rsquo;t afraid?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Turiya - The God State: Beyond Kundalini, Kriya Yoga &amp;amp; all Spirituality (Real Yoga)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How Psychology Works&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Being You: A New Science of Consciousness&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How to find love&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Make something wonderful&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;American Gods&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Tibetan Book of Living and Dying&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Logicomix&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Phoenix Project&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Art of Dying by Osho&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Old Man and the sea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zen Mind Beginners Mind&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Isa Upanishad&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chhandogya Upanishad&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Enlightenment is your nature&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;101 Essays That Will Change the Way You Think&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;books-in-progress&#34;&gt;Books In Progress:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;remnants-from-last-year&#34;&gt;Remnants from Last Year&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dhando Investor [ Not in that mental state of value investing rn ]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lives of the Stoics [ Got enough philosophy to be useful ]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meditations by Marcus Aurelius [ Same with meditations ]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Code Breaker by Walter Issacson [ Excited upto the point of decision for a Nobel Prize. Felt like that was all I needed ]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Krishnamurti&amp;rsquo;s Notebooks [ Needs absorption rather than completion ]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dream Yourself Awake [ Practice is more important. Only after mastering certain techniques, I will move forward ]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Monk who sold his Ferrari [ Started re-reading but dropped it ]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;newly-added&#34;&gt;Newly added&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Love Her Wild&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Sun and her flowers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Milk and Honey&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zen and The Art of Motorcycle Maintenance [ Too much zen already :P ]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Indian Philosophy [ It&amp;rsquo;s a big one. So much information, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to just process ]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Book of Secrets by Osho [ About techniques, no point in finishing the book ]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mulamadhyamkarika: Wisdom of the Middle Way by Nagarjuna [ Really intrigued by first chapter but cannot get time to contemplate on the ideas, pretty complex ]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oxford Handbook on Philosophy of Death [ Philosophy needs decent time to digest through introspection and speculation, which I currently don&amp;rsquo;t have ]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Head First Design Patterns&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Little Book about OS Development&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The God Delusion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Godel Escher Bach: An Eternal Golden Braid [ Really beautiful ideas which I really want to absorb, rather than read ]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt, Fat, Acid, Heat: A Science of Cooking&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Beginning of Infinity&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Design of Everyday Things&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lokpriya Sayar aur Unki Sayari&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Catch 22&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I read word &amp;ldquo;Bardo&amp;rdquo; for the first time in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Godel Escher Bach: An Eternal Golden Braid&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. When I read &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Tibetan Book of Dying and Living&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, I found out that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bardo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was a Tibetan word taken into English, and has a very big significance in Tibetan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tibetans are very clear about stages after death, re-incarnation, enlightenment on par with our clarity about daily tasks we do.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The more I read about neuroscience, the more I love reading philosophy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On Sanskrit and Sanskrit Texts:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sanskrit Grammar is such an elegant topic that was written a long time ago. I have no problem with people rejecting anything, but if we have no appreciation for the roots that we gave to the world, we are losing our identity into it. Sanskrit Grammar is one of the first complete grammar of any language in the world. Very elaborate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I am more intrigued by Eastern Philosophy because it&amp;rsquo;s easy to understand, easy because it fills gaps from our traditions, other related stories like Puranas, and folklores. Since Nepali language is derived from Sanskrit as well, I can contemplate some ideas from Sanskrit into my mind directly too. I have at least learned primitive level Sanskrit Grammar.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Most of the Buddhist texts were originally written in Sanskrit and Pali. Still to this day, Tibetans read both Sanskrit and Tibetan translation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In Nepal and India, we see Hinduism as this giant ball of tradition. We, as intellectuals, need to be able to separate contemporary usefulness of traditions from philosophy, and give it a fair chance without making it a mockery by comparing it with Western Philosophy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Upanishads are the lesser known beautiful extracts of Hindu tradition that comes under &lt;strong&gt;Vedanta&lt;/strong&gt;. Upanishads are called &lt;strong&gt;Vedanta&lt;/strong&gt; [ The End of Vedas ] because it&amp;rsquo;s said that they contain all the teachings of Veda in a more succinct form. Philosophical foods of thought that have been neglected because it&amp;rsquo;s hard to make philosophy a part of tradition unlike stories ( a.k.a Puranas ). There are many Upanishads, but 108 principal ones. Among them, 9 or 11 are said to be of significant importance. They are just like a few poems long.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Make Something Wonderful by Steve Jobs is a simple yet beautiful book on how Steve&amp;rsquo;s mind worked. And, it really is inspiring for someone who wants to build stuff for people.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Every school should teach &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Read a Book&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Reading is not just memorizing or marking something as complete. Reading is much more. And it depends on what you are reading. You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t read everything the same way. Like Francis Bacon said, &amp;ldquo;Some books are to be tasted, others to be swallowed, and some few to be chewed and digested.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s easier said than done.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Having a kindle really helps me because I can pick and drop books at any time without feeling guilty about it. I usually have around 200 books on my kindle.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you are curious about getting overview and some details into theory of consciousness, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Being You&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by Anil Seth is a great book. I loved his talks through the years, and this is a good digest of the whole field of consciousness and his theory of it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Read Psychology so you can understand your mind better. Reading Psychology + Meditating helps me clarify a lot of my confusions, and helps me accept conclusions that I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like accepting.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I have been pretty intrigued by death for a year or two now because I see it as hindrance to my true fulfillment. How can I truly be if I am always running away from something invisible? I still have amends to make, but a lot of ideas have been still like a lake on my mind. It&amp;rsquo;s not that the waves don&amp;rsquo;t come, but they settle quickly. I hope to be in equanimity with death soon enough, so that I can truly live.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zen is nothing more nothing less than mindfulness. There can be a thousand teachings and koans, but the essence is to simply be. The closest example of Zen that you can understand is Kung Fu Panda. Compare Master Shifu, Po, and Master Oogway; right in that comparison is answer to what Zen is. Knowing is one thing; accepting is another which you can learn from Shifu.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I am really loving &lt;strong&gt;Godel Escher Bach: An Eternal Golden Braid&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have any recommendations, or want certain recommendations; hit me up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My relationship with my body</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2023/01/my-relationship-with-my-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2023/01/my-relationship-with-my-body/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all identify our bodies as &amp;ldquo;my body&amp;rdquo; and &lt;strong&gt;not me directly&lt;/strong&gt;. The whole idea of this blog post revolves around this idea. The purpose of this blog post is to establish an idea on how to build healthier lifestyle based on this concept.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not like we intentionally don&amp;rsquo;t want to build healthier habits. We try to pick up exercise habits, but we are too lazy to work on it. We eat haphazardly, and without any consideration to our health. It&amp;rsquo;s a very universal problem. So, I had the same problem. On top of that, I have always been a person low in Conscientiousness, which means I used to have a hard time pushing my goals to myself if I was the only one responsible for it. Finally, I found a way that worked for me that might work for you too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R Programming 105- Unsupervised Learning</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/10/r-programming-105-unsupervised-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/10/r-programming-105-unsupervised-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;k-means-clustering&#34;&gt;K Means Clustering&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-R&#34; data-lang=&#34;R&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;res &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;kmeans&lt;/span&gt;(x,&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;              centers &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; num,&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;              nstart &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; num,&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;              iter.max &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;res&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;cluster &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# gives the cluster number for each data point&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;(res) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# prints cluster means, cluster, sum of squares by cluster and so on.&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arguments&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Centers is the number of clusters to make.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nstart is used to run algorithm multiple times to improve the odds of the best model.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Iter.max is used to set the number of steps to do when creating each clusters.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Visualizing output&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R Programming 105- Supervised Learning 1</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/10/r-programming-105-supervised-learning-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/10/r-programming-105-supervised-learning-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;aggregate-by-column&#34;&gt;Aggregate by column&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-R&#34; data-lang=&#34;R&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;aggregate&lt;/span&gt;(col_name &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;~&lt;/span&gt; by_column_name, data &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; df_name, mean)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can use other functions instead of mean as well. The variable after tilde is what the aggregation is done with respect to. If &lt;em&gt;by_column_name&lt;/em&gt; is continent, the above code will calculate the mean for all continents for given column: e.g. age or anything like that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;nearest-neighbors&#34;&gt;Nearest Neighbors&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-R&#34; data-lang=&#34;R&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;library&lt;/span&gt;(class)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;knn&lt;/span&gt;(train &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; train_data, test &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; test_data, cl&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;vector_train_labels)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Confusion Matrix&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-R&#34; data-lang=&#34;R&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;table&lt;/span&gt;(actual_classes, pred_classes)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This creates a confusion matrix based on number of observations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R Programming 105- Supervised Learning 2 Regression</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/10/r-programming-105-supervised-learning-2-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/10/r-programming-105-supervised-learning-2-regression/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;gain-curve&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;org-todo todo TODO&#34;&gt;TODO&lt;/span&gt; Gain Curve&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;writing-formulas&#34;&gt;Writing formulas&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-R&#34; data-lang=&#34;R&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;formula_obj &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/span&gt; var1 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;~&lt;/span&gt; var2&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;formula_obj &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/span&gt; var1 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;~&lt;/span&gt; var2 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; var3&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;formula_obj &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;as.formula&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;var1 ~ var2&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-information-about-the-model&#34;&gt;Getting information about the model&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-R&#34; data-lang=&#34;R&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;(model_var)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;summary&lt;/span&gt;(model_var)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;broom&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;glance&lt;/span&gt;(model_var)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sigr&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;wrapFTest&lt;/span&gt;(model_var)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;print&lt;/em&gt; shows the basic formula used and the coefficients for the model.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;summary&lt;/em&gt; shows the formula, coefficients, residuals as well as probabilistic statistics such as R^2 value and so on.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;glance&lt;/em&gt; shows the whole data from summary in the form of nice dataframe with columns such as &lt;strong&gt;df.residual&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;sigma&lt;/strong&gt; and so on.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;wrapFTest&lt;/em&gt; shows the most relevant details of the model.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;predicting-using-the-model&#34;&gt;Predicting using the model&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-R&#34; data-lang=&#34;R&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;predict&lt;/span&gt;(model, newdata &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; new_data_vals)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;collinearity&#34;&gt;Collinearity&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The variables assumed to be independent might not be independent after all.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Unusually high collinearity may make model unstable though.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;gain-curve&#34;&gt;Gain curve&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The gain curve is important in sorting the outcome rather than making all predictions correct. Checks if model&amp;rsquo;s predictions sort in the same order as the true outcome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
