<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Alok&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Alok&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 07:02:53 +0545</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dragarok.github.io/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Anything You Want: 40 Lessons for a New Kind of Entrepreneur</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/anything-you-want-40-lessons-for-a-new-kind-of-entrepreneur/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 07:02:53 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/anything-you-want-40-lessons-for-a-new-kind-of-entrepreneur/</guid>
      <description>### Author: Sivers, Derek
  loc 70 - Don’t pursue business just for your own gain. Only answer the calls for help.
  loc 89 - It’s not that distributors were evil. It was just an awful system, and I wanted nothing to do with it. So when the big online record stores told me they couldn’t sell my CD directly, I thought, “Ah, screw it. I’ll just set up my own online store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Courage to Be Disliked</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/ichiro-kishimifumitake-koga/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 07:48:18 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/ichiro-kishimifumitake-koga/</guid>
      <description>### Author: Ichiro Kishimi;Fumitake Koga
  loc 143 - That is not because the world is complicated. It’s because you are making the world complicated. YOUTH: I am? PHILOSOPHER: None of us live in an objective world, but instead in a subjective world that we ourselves have given meaning to. The world you see is different from the one I see, and it’s impossible to share your world with anyone else</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Astronomy Book</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/dk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 02:30:19 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/dk/</guid>
      <description>### Author: DK
  loc 216 - &amp;ldquo;You have to have the imagination to recognize a discovery when you make one.&amp;rdquo; Clyde Tombaugh
  loc 225 - &amp;ldquo;What a wonderful and amazing scheme have we here of the magnificent vastness of the universe.&amp;rdquo; Christiaan Huygens
  loc 235 - in 1979, the first example of a gravitational lens was identified, when the image of a quasar was seen to be double due to the presence of a galaxy along the line of sight, again as relativity had predicted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eat That Frog!: 21 Great Ways to Stop Procrastinating and Get More Done in Less Time</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/eat-that-frog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 02:30:01 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/eat-that-frog/</guid>
      <description>### Author: Tracy, Brian
  loc 70 - Then I did something that changed my life. I began to ask successful people what they were doing that enabled them to be more productive and earn more money than me. And they told me.
  loc 88 - The ability to concentrate singlemindedly on your most important task, to do it well and to finish it completely, is the key to great success, achievement, respect, status, and happiness in life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unbearable Lightness of Being</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/milan-kundera/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 02:28:33 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/milan-kundera/</guid>
      <description>### Author: Milan Kundera
  loc 306 - The idea of eternal return
  loc 308 - Putting it negatively, the myth of eternal return states that a life which disappears once and for all, which does not return, is like a shadow, without weight, dead in advance, and whether it was horrible, beautiful, or sublime, its horror, sublimity, and beauty mean nothing
  loc 332 - This reconciliation with Hitler reveals the profound moral perversity of a world that rests essentially on the nonexistence of return, for in this world everything is pardoned in advance and therefore everything cynically permitted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kundalini – an Untold Story: A Himalayan Mystic&#39;s Insight Into the Power of Kundalini and Chakra Sadhana</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/om-swami/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 02:28:19 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/om-swami/</guid>
      <description>### Author: OM Swami
  loc 92 - The science of the kundalini is an ancient vidya that has been passed through an oral tradition in strict disciplic succession to worthy recipients. The science remains just as intact today. All it requires is for one to walk the path with great determination and tenacity.
  loc 618 - When you don’t react, a sense of ease arises. Resistance goes away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can&#39;t Stop Talking</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/quiet-the-power-of-introverts-in-a-world-that-cant-stop-talking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 02:27:55 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/quiet-the-power-of-introverts-in-a-world-that-cant-stop-talking/</guid>
      <description>### Author: Cain, Susan
  loc 121 - Introverts living under the Extrovert Ideal are like women in a man’s world, discounted because of a trait that goes to the core of who they are.
  loc 226 - Introverts are drawn to the inner world of thought and feeling, said Jung, extroverts to the external life of people and activities. Introverts focus on the meaning they make of the events swirling around them; extroverts plunge into the events themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gitanjali</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/rabindranath-tagore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 02:27:38 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/rabindranath-tagore/</guid>
      <description>### Author: Rabindranath Tagore
  loc 208 - Indeed, when he is speaking of children, so much a part of himself this quality seems, one is not certain that he is not also speaking of the saints, “They build their houses with sand and they play with empty shells. With withered leaves they weave their boats and smilingly float them on the vast deep. Children have their play on the seashore of worlds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Siddhartha</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/siddhartha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 02:27:19 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/siddhartha/</guid>
      <description>### Author: Hermann Hesse
  loc 747 - &amp;ldquo;No, Samana, I am not afraid of this. Did any Samana or Brahman ever fear, someone might come and grab him and steal his learning, and his religious devotion, and his depth of thought? No, for they are his very own, and he would only give away from those whatever he is willing to give and to whomever he is willing to give.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Charisma Myth: How Anyone Can Master the Art and Science of Personal Magnetism</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/the-charisma-myth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 02:26:54 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/the-charisma-myth/</guid>
      <description>### Author: Cabane, Olivia Fox
  loc 111 - When we first meet someone, we instinctively assess whether that person is a potential friend or foe and whether they have the power to enact those intentions.
  loc 114 - When you meet a charismatic person, you get the impression that they have a lot of power and they like you a lot.
  loc 167 - Lower the intonation of your voice at the end of your sentences.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>