<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Alok&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Alok&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 03:08:39 +0545</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dragarok.github.io/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>13 STEPS TO BLOODY GOOD LUCK</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/13-steps-to-bloody-good-luck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 03:08:39 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/13-steps-to-bloody-good-luck/</guid>
      <description>### Author: SANGHI, ASHWIN
loc 173 - eventually get married. Being at the right place
loc 206 - Pretty much everything we do to make ourselves lucky or unlucky can be traced back to attitude and approach.
loc 221 - On the other hand, the lucky group approached the task with less anxiety, greater optimism and in a far more relaxed frame of mind. They did not see the need to compete, and this relaxed attitude allowed them to observe beyond the immediate task at hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brief History of Everyone who Ever Lived: The Stories in Our Genes</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/a-brief-history-of-everyone-who-ever-lived-the-stories-in-our-genes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 03:08:38 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/a-brief-history-of-everyone-who-ever-lived-the-stories-in-our-genes/</guid>
      <description>### Author: Rutherford, Adam
loc 1 - Here two sets of multiplexers select register which perform input data for ALU. A decoder selects destination register by enabling its load input. The function select in ALU determines the particular operation that to be performed
loc 1 - For an example to perform the operation: R3  R1 + R2 1. MUX A selector (SELA): to place the content of R1 into bus A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Common-Sense Guide to Data Structures and Algorithms: Level Up Your Core Programming Skills</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/a-common-sense-guide-to-data-structures-and-algorithms-level-up-your-core-programming-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 03:08:37 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/a-common-sense-guide-to-data-structures-and-algorithms-level-up-your-core-programming-skills/</guid>
      <description>### Author: Wengrow, Jay
loc 678 - Simply put, O(log N) is the Big O way of describing an algorithm that increases one step each time the data is doubled.
loc 1542 - Looking up a value in a hash table has an efficiency of O(1) on average, as it takes just one step.
loc 1555 - The truth is that a hash function needs to meet only one criterion to be valid: a hash function must convert the same string to the same number every single time it’s applied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to the Good Life: The Ancient Art of Stoic Joy</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/a-guide-to-the-good-life-the-ancient-art-of-stoic-joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 03:08:36 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/a-guide-to-the-good-life-the-ancient-art-of-stoic-joy/</guid>
      <description>### Author: Irvine, William B.
loc 162 - we are unlikely to have a good and meaningful life unless we can overcome our insatiability.
loc 441 - Students who knew logic could detect the fallacies committed by others and thereby prevail over them in arguments.
loc 443 - And besides providing explanations of natural phenomena, as modern physics does, Stoic physics was concerned with what we would call theology.
loc 448 - Stoic ethics, in contrast, is what is called eudaemonistic ethics, from the Greek eu meaning “good” and daimon meaning “spirit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Concurrency (Android Deep Dive)</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/android-concurrency-android-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 03:08:35 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/android-concurrency-android-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>### Author: Meike, G. Blake
loc 376 - Synchronization is the basic mechanism through which multiple Java threads share state in such a way that the result of the interaction is deterministic.
loc 400 - A correct concurrent program is one that abides by the contract for maintaining an illusion.
loc 401 - Negotiation between application programmers and hardware developers produce a language, and that language is a contract. The application developers get their illusion of sequential execution, something about which they can reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Design Patterns and Best Practice</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/android-design-patterns-and-best-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 03:08:35 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/android-design-patterns-and-best-practice/</guid>
      <description>### Author: Mew, Kyle
loc 330 - This is not to say that code can be simply cut and pasted from one project to another but that the concepts themselves can be used over and over again in many different situations.
loc 333 - When a developer describes a structure as say, an adapter or a facade, other developers will understand what this means and will immediately recognize the structure and purpose of the code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Programming in a Day 2nd Edition! The Power Guide for Beginners In Android App Programming (Android, Android Programming, App Development, Android … App Programming, Rails, Ruby Programming)</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/android-programming-in-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 03:08:34 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/android-programming-in-a-day/</guid>
      <description>### Author: Key, Sam
loc 96 - An Android operating system, regardless of version number, is composed of five software components. They are the Linux kernel, libraries, Android runtime, application framework, and applications.
loc 113 - Just above the kernel are the Android libraries. In programming, libraries are reusable program components that make program development and computer operations easier. A few of the known libraries in Android are surface manager, media framework, SQLite, OpenGL, ES, FreeType, WebKit, SGL, SSL, and libc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antenna-Theory-Analysis-and-Design</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/antenna-theory-analysis-and-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 03:08:34 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/antenna-theory-analysis-and-design/</guid>
      <description>### Author:
loc 28 - However, when the waves are radiated, they form closed loops and there are no charges to sustain their existence. This leads us to conclude that electric charges are required to excite the ﬁelds but are not needed to sustain them and may exist in their absence. This is in direct analogy with water waves
loc 30 - interaction. With today’s advanced numerical and computational methods, and animation and visualization software and hardware, this dilemma can, to a large extent, be minimized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tale of Two Cities</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/a-tale-of-two-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 03:08:33 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/a-tale-of-two-cities/</guid>
      <description>### Author: Dickens, Charles
loc 160 - A wonderful fact to reflect upon, that every human creature is constituted to be that profound secret and mystery to every other. A solemn consideration, when I enter a great city by night, that every one of those darkly clustered houses encloses its own secret; that every room in every one of them encloses its own secret; that every beating heart in the hundreds of thousands of breasts there, is, in some of its imaginings, a secret to the heart nearest it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anything You Want: 40 Lessons for a New Kind of Entrepreneur</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/anything-you-want-40-lessons-for-a-new-kind-of-entrepreneur/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 03:08:33 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/anything-you-want-40-lessons-for-a-new-kind-of-entrepreneur/</guid>
      <description>### Author: Sivers, Derek
loc 70 - Don’t pursue business just for your own gain. Only answer the calls for help.
loc 89 - It’s not that distributors were evil. It was just an awful system, and I wanted nothing to do with it. So when the big online record stores told me they couldn’t sell my CD directly, I thought, “Ah, screw it. I’ll just set up my own online store.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
