<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Braindumps on Alok&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Braindumps on Alok&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 07:54:57 +0545</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RA</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/08/ra/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 07:54:57 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/08/ra/</guid>
      <description>Basic terminologies:  Dimensions Facts  Table and table naming conventions  initial 3 letter prefix: DWH, ODS etc. Content: e.g. PRD, SLS Dimension or Fact: D, F Granularity : Department, day/week etc. Suffix as use case: Lookup vs Base Vs Aggregate vs Matrix Naming: data region + dimension_or_fact + content + granularity + usage  Column naming:  Naming: Attribute or measure + data type Attribute: Price etc. Data type: KEY, ID, DESC Maintenance columns: insert timestamp, update, close, close_dt Business calendar: 4-4-5 or 4-5-4 or 5-4-4 and 13 period calendar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips from entrepreneurs</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/08/tips-from-entrepreneurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/08/tips-from-entrepreneurs/</guid>
      <description>Being an entrepreneur old fashioned way I Became an Entrepreneur the Old-Fashioned Way: Getting Fired | by Todd Brison
 Companies are designed to make you feel rich, powerful, and successful. They are also designed to keep you from remembering all of that wealth, power, and status can be ripped away at a moment’s notice. Getting fired can take people to pursue their side gig.  Tips   Work harder on streams of income</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Reading 3 pass</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/07/paper-reading-3-pass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 12:07:48 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/07/paper-reading-3-pass/</guid>
      <description>Reference: https://codearsonist.com/reading-for-programmers
3 pass Overview:  Verify  Value Background   Grasp  Thought Process Highlights Diagram Unknowns References   Understand  Holes Implementations Notes    Process Verify  This provides High level view of the contents. Start with references usually. Mark the cited papers I&amp;rsquo;ve read as to get previous notes I have made and verify the background. Title, Abstract, Introduction&amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Read very carefully Scan through to find diagrams, equations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anatomy directions</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/05/anatomy-directions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/05/anatomy-directions/</guid>
      <description>Normal anatomy terms    Term Description     Anterior At or near the front of the body (front view)   Posterior At or near the back of the body (back view)   Midline An imaginary vertical line that divides the body equally (right down the middle)   Lateral Farther from midline (side view)   Medial Nearer to midline (side view)   Superior Toward the head/upper part of a structure (bird’s-eye view, looking down)   Inferior Away from the head/lower part of a structure (bottom view, looking up)   Superficial Close to the surface of the body   Deep Away from the surface of the body   Proximal Nearer to the origination of a structure   Distal Farther from the origination of a structure    Neuroanatomical axes Anatomical axes, planes and localisations in the human brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Commands</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/05/git-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 07:10:51 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/05/git-commands/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ndash;tags: Useful &amp;ndash;references: https://learngitbranching.js.org/
Commands   git add : tracking with git
  git status : current status of tracked, untracked, changed, committed files.
  git add filename.extension
  (only after making the file it can be done)
  double add command - stages the new changes
  git commit
  git add . -&amp;gt; all files are committed
  git add *.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large Scale Network Embedding</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/05/large-scale-network-embedding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 03:40:13 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/05/large-scale-network-embedding/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ndash;tags: Graph Embedding Techniques
LINE: Large scale Network Embedding &amp;ndash; Explicitly define two functions for 1st and 2nd order proximity. &amp;ndash; EMpirically,found that the 2nd order proximity performed better and improved accuracy. &amp;ndash; Goal: to decrease KL divergence between the input and the embedding distributions &amp;ndash; Since the algorithm has to define new functions for each increasing order of proximity, LINE doesn’t perform very well if the application needs an understanding of node community structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8086</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/05/8086/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 01:01:54 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/05/8086/</guid>
      <description>one pass assembler: converts whole at one, jmp instruction references made after assembly two pass: converts in two steps : first generates a symbol table of names and labels used in programs and calculate their relative addresses, then converts the instructions into machine code in the next cycle of assembly, more efficient and easier than first
Linking:
 can link multiple obj files into one and forms exe file additional files that can be produced by the linker .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KdeConnect I3</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/05/kdeconnect-i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/05/kdeconnect-i3/</guid>
      <description>Firewall sudo ufw allow 1714:1764/udp sudo ufw allow 1714:1764/tcp
Installation pacman -S kdeconnect yay -S indicator-kdeconnect I3 settings exec --no-startup-id indicator-kdeconnect I3 additional If the above one is not working
exec --no-startup-id /usr/lib/kdeconnectd </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Songs</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/04/songs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 11:04:41 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/04/songs/</guid>
      <description>Eurielle - Song of Durin &amp;ndash; Hobbit Part 1-3 Jade Bird - Ruins</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Higgs Boson</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/04/beyond-higgs-boson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/04/beyond-higgs-boson/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ndash; link: Beyond Higgs: The Wild Frontier of Particle Physics - YouTube - Brave
What are these people looking for?  Supersymmetry  Mathematical idea: Not still experimentally verified. Pencil standing on it&amp;rsquo;s tip Analogy: Though people found the Higgs out there, there is still no understanding of how the higgs is standing in the standard model. Physicists are looking for the support for the pencil if it is being held by a string or being held by hand.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>