<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Startup on </title>
    <link>https://dragarok.github.io/tags/startup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Startup on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 02:26:33 +0545</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dragarok.github.io/tags/startup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Lean Startup: How Today&#39;s Entrepreneurs Use Continuous Innovation to Create Radically Successful Businesses</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/the-lean-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 02:26:33 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/the-lean-startup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;### Author: Ries, Eric&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;loc 107 - There is a mythmaking industry hard at work to sell us that story, but I have come to believe that the story is false, the product of selection bias and after-the-fact rationalization.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;loc 119 - Entrepreneurship is a kind of management. No, you didn’t read that wrong. We have wildly divergent associations with these two words, entrepreneurship and management. Lately, it seems that one is cool, innovative, and exciting and the other is dull, serious, and bland. It is time to look past these preconceptions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero to One: Notes on Startups, or How to Build the Future</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/books/zero-to-one-notes-on-startups-or-how-to-build-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 02:22:52 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/books/zero-to-one-notes-on-startups-or-how-to-build-the-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;### Author: Peter Thiel;Blake Masters&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;loc 123 - in business, small groups of people bound together by a sense of mission have changed the world for the better. The easiest explanation for this is negative: it’s hard to develop new things in big organizations, and it’s even harder to do it by yourself. Bureaucratic hierarchies move slowly, and entrenched interests shy away from risk. In the most dysfunctional organizations, signaling that work is being done becomes a better strategy for career advancement than actually doing work (if this describes your company, you should quit now).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
