<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oracle on </title>
    <link>https://dragarok.github.io/tags/oracle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oracle on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 07:54:57 +0545</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dragarok.github.io/tags/oracle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>RA</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/08/ra/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 07:54:57 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/08/ra/</guid>
      <description>Basic terminologies: Dimensions Facts Table and table naming conventions initial 3 letter prefix: DWH, ODS etc. Content: e.g. PRD, SLS Dimension or Fact: D, F Granularity : Department, day/week etc. Suffix as use case: Lookup vs Base Vs Aggregate vs Matrix Naming: data region + dimension_or_fact + content + granularity + usage Column naming: Naming: Attribute or measure + data type Attribute: Price etc. Data type: KEY, ID, DESC Maintenance columns: insert timestamp, update, close, close_dt Business calendar: 4-4-5 or 4-5-4 or 5-4-4 and 13 period calendar.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ODI</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/04/odi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 16:00:19 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/04/odi/</guid>
      <description>Full package for ETL Automation tool: UC4 RMS Server Database These work together; ODI isn&amp;rsquo;t standalone. All stuffs may be installed in the same RMS server. Jobs Handled by (ksh) scripts to run different jobs UC4 Scheduler Agent: defined in uc4 to connect to RMS server. defines path of scripts ODI agent Connect between server &amp;amp; ODI Can also automate UC4 tasks in newer versions. Architecture Design Mapping Transform Making of Project Operator Logging Status of jobs Topology Defining connections : physical and logical Physical connections ==&amp;gt; Mapped to logical connections Data model ==&amp;gt; Map table columns to table columns and so on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Warehouse</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/04/warehouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 15:59:59 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/04/warehouse/</guid>
      <description>Basic terminologies:&#xA;Dimensions Facts&#xA;Table and table naming conventions initial 3 letter prefix: DWH, ODS etc. Content: e.g. PRD, SLS Dimension or Fact: D, F Granularity : Department, day/week etc. Suffix as use case: Lookup vs Base Vs Aggregate vs Matrix Naming: data region + dimension_or_fact + content + granularity + usage&#xA;Column naming: Naming: Attribute or measure + data type Attribute: Price etc. Data type: KEY, ID, DESC&#xA;Maintenance columns: insert timestamp, update, close, close_dt</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>obiee</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/04/obiee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 15:59:53 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/04/obiee/</guid>
      <description>Steps Catalog &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Get to columns and filters. Change defaults tab to criteria save as give a proper name for result change all columns and filters as necessary. save again go to results then. export results. if &amp;gt; 2500 : export to csv. Edit the sheet RMS Sales recon Tran data In tran_data we have item, units, tran_code as major fields. if it belongs to a pack, then it has a ref_pack_no which is a packitem object.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
