<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Speaking on </title>
    <link>https://dragarok.github.io/tags/speaking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Speaking on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 15:59:18 +0545</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dragarok.github.io/tags/speaking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Public Speaking</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/04/public-speaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 15:59:18 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/braindump/2020/04/public-speaking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Public Speaking: Is it really hard or do you make it harder yourself?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Points to be noted while public speaking&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Make a nice and clear pace. Don’t go too fast or too slow.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Take time for audience to make them comprehend your point nice and clear to go.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Make a certain dramatic pose when you assert a strong point so that people can clearly understand and appreciate your point.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Don’t think too harsh on the subject matter so that you get confused while speaking.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hand gestures is about balance or something like that. Certain gestures don’t look so good. Don’t be a frozen speaker.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Working together to make your voice understand to the people. Large audience 45 degree, 135 degree, 90 degree.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Facial expressions can depict powerful messages so make sure that it matches the way you and the content of your speech.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Movement is best when transitioning from one point to another point. Don’t move and move back and forth.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Intentional body movements and facial gestures can clarify the topic more than any words do.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Appearance matters since sloppy people can’t attract people to listen to them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Word Choice: umm and filler words are to be transformed into the pause.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Colorful words: This person is travelling down the road of mediocre life: the words that evokes emotions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
