<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on </title>
        <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on </description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://dragarok.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Satya Poem: After a decade</title>
            <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2025/10/satya-poem-after-a-decade/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2025/10/satya-poem-after-a-decade/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The context is this: I wrote this poem as an extension of my emotions 10 years ago.
The poem&amp;rsquo;s titled &amp;ldquo;Satya&amp;rdquo; and was the first poem on my blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neither am I a poet, nor a storyteller. I wrote what I genuinely felt at that time. And this was close to when Gadhimai Mela was about to happen and there was a lot of news about &lt;strong&gt;Bali Pratha&lt;/strong&gt; needing to stop and so on. It triggered something that was already brewing inside me vehemently, into words. This is my commentary on my own writing after 10 years of seeking, learning, and coming home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The context is this: I wrote this poem as an extension of my emotions 10 years ago.
The poem&rsquo;s titled &ldquo;Satya&rdquo; and was the first poem on my blog.</p>
<p>Neither am I a poet, nor a storyteller. I wrote what I genuinely felt at that time. And this was close to when Gadhimai Mela was about to happen and there was a lot of news about <strong>Bali Pratha</strong> needing to stop and so on. It triggered something that was already brewing inside me vehemently, into words. This is my commentary on my own writing after 10 years of seeking, learning, and coming home.</p>
<p>I will explain each paragraph one by one: what still is true, what I have learned that I didn&rsquo;t a decade ago, and so on. This will probably be a long one, but a worthy one if you genuinely are looking for yourself too. And I don&rsquo;t think I will write much on Spirituality from now on because my path is laid somewhere else. And there is more than enough written out there for an ardent seeker already.</p>
<p>I am just enjoying living. If you have questions, you can personally ask me. No time for arguments, all the time for those who truly need it. Apart from that, I hope you find peace within you. I bow down to the divinity in all of you. Lets get started here:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>आकाङ्क्षाका पानाहरुमा </br>
समेटिएको यो जीवनमा</br>
च्यातिएका ती पानाहरु</br>
स्वयमहित्को तान्डवसँगै</br>
कुल्चिएका भावनाहरु ।</br></p>
</blockquote>
<p>The wise ones say the Universe was born out of desire: a desire to find itself, know itself, know its limits. And so it does create these projections to understand what it can be. And that&rsquo;s life summarized as well. And its true that each individual is fragmented, and torn; not because of themselves but by design. The same design that can recognize it as whole too. It&rsquo;s just you who is unable to recognize this whole. To this, there is this Sanskrit quote that summarizes what you might not have known:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>ॐ पूर्णमदः पूर्णमिदं पूर्णात्पूर्णमुदच्यते ।</br>
पूर्णस्य पूर्णमादाय पूर्णमेवावशिष्यते ॥</br>
ॐ शान्तिः शान्तिः शान्तिः ॥</br></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Meaning: This is complete, that is complete. From this whole, that whole arises.</br>
When you take this whole out of that, it&rsquo;s indeed complete yet again.
Peace, Peace, Peace.</br></p>
<p>This is the idea. You don&rsquo;t think that is possible because you didn&rsquo;t assume the nature of this primordial whole which is uncaused. Just by being uncaused, its not graspable by logic. We understand linearity and causality pretty easily. You already know how brain fuck time travel movies can be. Think of it like that. </br>
Think about the first thing that existed and how. Contemplate, introspect, and study at the same time. Whatever answer there is, it will find you.</br></p>
<p>So, coming to this, we who live our lives in misery, are these torn pages. This is not me saying it. This is Buddha saying &ldquo;Life is misery&rdquo;. And to why, everyone says its because you live too tight with your ego. Anything and everything hurts you. Your intuition, your emotions are bulldozered by someone else all the time. That&rsquo;s why it is indeed miserable in general.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>तिनै जलेका पानाहरु</br>
धुँवा बनी उडेको छ</br>
संसार जस्तो भएपनि</br>
अदृश्यतामा रमेकोछ ।</br></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Yes, the smell of misery is everywhere. The burnt smell is flowing here and there. We are all emitting that smell, and its almost as if it has engulfed the whole atmosphere. And where is the fragrance? The fragrance is hiding itself in the safest position away from the burnt smell: as fire that burns it.
The smell of burning comes because you know there is somewhere fire that is burning. And that fire is your inner recognition: your inner peace lying within you. The smell that&rsquo;s reaching your nose is telling you to look for that inner fire which has hidden itself but the symptom of that fire is that smell of burning itself.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>हिमालका ती कोप्चारामा</br>
हिउँसँगै जमेकोछ ।।</br></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Yes, its frozen right there. Its not moving. Its still hiding behind that stiffness in all of us.</br></p>
<blockquote>
<p>सुरको धुनमा बज्दा यसलाई</br>
शब्दकोशमा खोजेपछि</br>
आफुलाई नचाहरि</br>
धर्मग्रन्थ रटेपछि</br>
न्यायका ती किताबले नै</br>
सत्यतालाई ढाकेपछि ।</br></p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is one of these things one would say out of anger too. Beautiful words, but I didn&rsquo;t know anything at that time. It just was written through my being. Neither did I know scriptures, nor did I know where the music was.</br></p>
<p>Its heavily true that you try to find words to expressions that you cannot understand. Like the origin of universe, there are things which logic can&rsquo;t hold much longer, but your being knows exactly what its talking about.</br></p>
<p>If we both have experienced Love, we both understand a lover looking at the moon and appreciating the moon as their lovers. Or them looking at lover&rsquo;s eyes and comparing it to the moon. We both didn&rsquo;t communicate in words. We communicated in that imperfect expression of love which is pointing to the feeling that we understood in ourselves. </br></p>
<p>That is the same with inner Truth. It can&rsquo;t be expressed in all these words I say. Even Rabindranath Tagore was not able to do it in Gitanjali. But when I read him, I see the same fragrance. Being which has touched the source at least, and wants to get engrossed in it.</br></p>
<p>In today&rsquo;s world, not enough people are reading scriptures, yet claiming facts by taking one line/page, and making judgements about it. The wise ones have found Truth in all of them, because the Truth is right there in all of us.</br></p>
<p>How can it not be in one of the best expressions of us? If you don&rsquo;t have time to study, better stay away from it. If you want to comment, better study. Just imagine a 12 year old coming at Scientific Literature with 8th grader knowledge. A lot of things in his book were written to simplify it for that 12 year old, but that doesn&rsquo;t mean its not true, or its not representing Truth.</br></p>
<p>This is not me saying I know it, but this is the pattern that I have unraveled within these books. I have recognized a few lines, and these are enough pointers for a bigger mystery. </br>
Science is one of the best portals to Truth. If you want to negate religion and scriptures, accept Science as the only Truth. It will take you to your being faster than almost all of those who follow religion. </br></p>
<p>But, if you already are a skeptic, find your own boxes to put reasoning and your spirituality into. Find contradictions. Don&rsquo;t open these boxes when you need them just to win arguments. Soon enough, they will start talking to you. You need to give ideas time to settle.</br></p>
<p>Law, order, society, rituals, traditions, ideas etc. There is bit of truth in all of that but someone will disagree to it all the time. Its an attempt to localize answer for easing our lives. So, understand most of it as that.</br></p>
<p>Just focus on finding something that is not localized; something that doesn&rsquo;t change if I put you in Nepal or US or Japan. That will be a good pointer for finding ideas that are universal. That is one good anchor to walk the walk.</br></p>
<blockquote>
<p>सत्य आज मरिसक्यो</br>
जीवनलाई छाडेपछि</br>
मृत्यु सत्य बनिसक्यो</br>
सत्य खोज्न थालेपछि ।।</br></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Haha, this is one of the funniest things about life. There is one simple truth that I can tell you as well.
<strong>&ldquo;To this day, everybody who has lived, has died, sooner or later.&rdquo;</strong>
Death is simply washing away of all there is. But even Buddha believed in reincarnation.</br>
Finding escape in death is easy, but only if it sure could be an escape.
Life is meant to be lived with such vigor and ecstasy knowing its going to come to an end eventually.</br>
Buddhist monks draw a Mandala out of sand, putting in all the effort for weeks for it to look flawless, only to wipe it off after completing it. That is not silly. That is a practice that gets closer to life than anything else. Just because we know that its going to extinguish doesn&rsquo;t mean we are stopped from creating beauty. We can create beauty with an understanding that it will perish.</br></p>
<p>When we create beauty with that idea, beauty stands by itself: glorious.</br>
And the way to live life is like that beauty. Those who live like that smell like Truth more than all those who are seeking it. Contradiction all the way, baby.</br></p>
<blockquote>
<p>गढिमाईको मन्दीरमा</br>
मृत्यु नै त सत्य बन्यो</br>
न्याय बन्यो धर्म बन्यो</br>
सत्य सँधै एक्लो बन्यो ।</br></p>
</blockquote>
<p>This will be my controversial take on this after studying this for some time. This is a thin moral line but I don&rsquo;t mind walking it.</br>
As long as you eat meat, its better if you eat it as offering to some force rather than eating it as is like an animal. Because that helps you understand and lower your ego better. At least, you are recognizing something bigger than you. Making it a festive in hopes to appease Goddess, not so much. FYI: Its not for the main deity that you think the sacrifice is for. <strong>Unless there is purity in your heart, much of it is a waste anyway.</strong></br></p>
<p><strong>And for those who realize, they don&rsquo;t even have to do a Sattvic Yajna or a ritual offering flowers. There is only one true offering: offering of your ego (false identity).</strong></br></p>
<p>For those who realize, there is no difference between eating meat/ not eating meat.
I don&rsquo;t want to expound or teach anything.
If you have a Guru, do what he tells you to do. If you don&rsquo;t, guide it with your own moral compass. </br></p>
<p>You become more sensitive when you don&rsquo;t eat. It eases your meditation as well. Stopping just at this.</br></br></p>
<blockquote>
<p>कतै मुस्कान लहरसँगै</br>
कतै रगत खोलो बग्यो</br>
आलो रगत चरुसँगै</br>
सत्य यज्ञ भष्म बन्यो ।</br></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Death is one simple truth that we all know. The reason why they put Tika of &ldquo;Bhasma** on their forehead in some traditions of Hinduism relates to this idea beautifully. You need to adore death as your personal friend. There are so many sects in Hinduism and Buddhism that meditate on the cremation ground. Death is but natural for them. Those who see it see everything as indifferent from one another.</p>
<p>Yes, truth is in that &ldquo;Bhasma**. I didn&rsquo;t know it at the time. I know it now. And its much pure than the best of temples you visit where people pretend to be, but have no true compassion.</p>
<p>All ideas of morality are fake if you don&rsquo;t have an internal moral compass.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>त्यै भष्मको कालो टीका</br>
धर्मको त प्रतिक बन्यो</br>
सत्य अब जलिसक्यो</br>
यो माटोलाई त्यागिसक्यो</br>
विनाशतिर लम्काएर</br>
संसारदेखि भागिसक्यो ।।</br></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Yes, this is the world we live in. Find those who don&rsquo;t pretend, who are raw. They might hurt you, they might pain you, but they will eventually lead you to truth. You shouldn&rsquo;t put on for anyone for it hides your being a little. Little by little, you forget who you are. You will be despised, desolate for doing so, but that&rsquo;s the path of Truth.</p>
<p><strong>Truth is personal. You cannot show it to someone who has closed their eyes by their own will.</strong>
</br></p>
<p>Just look at how Premanand Maharaj talks about his Bhakti. That is a smell most people can understand.</br></br></p>
<p>So, this is my conclusion. I have traveled far and wide within myself and the world to realize what I do today. I am raw here because you know that you can be, at least with yourself personally. It is the best weapon to tear through all illusions. </br></p>
<p><strong>A decade ago</strong>, I felt desolate, alone in my room. No idea where I was going, yet with almost everything that the world usually fights for. I had most of these things they wished, but it was only baggage for me. I didn&rsquo;t know who I was. The only time I felt home was when I was below the night sky, watching those stars. They made me feel like they were watching me, protecting me. I felt alone among all the people who knew me. And in that desolate moment, I couldn&rsquo;t see any light of truth anywhere. That&rsquo;s why I wrote that last verse.</p>
<p><strong>But today, I know that its almost everywhere for those who have the earnest eyes.</strong></br></p>
<p><strong>For those who don&rsquo;t lie, even to themselves.</strong></br></p>
<p><strong>For those who are sensitive enough to look for it even in the remotest of places. There are stories of Sufi saints living as Butchers, so open your eyes to the possibility.</strong></br></p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t lie to yourself, even as self-deprecating humor.</strong></br></p>
<p><strong>What you don&rsquo;t know, don&rsquo;t assume. Ask if you have to. Write your things down.</strong></br></p>
<p><strong>Be patient with answers. Some questions take years to get answered, some might get answered by next person you meet.</strong></br></p>
<p><strong>Always be listening heartily, not to answer, listen to listen.</strong></br></p>
<p><strong>Anchor yourselves in Truth and Truth alone. Sooner or later, you will find that what you are looking for.</strong></br></p>
<p><strong>Be empathetic, be brave.</strong></br></p>
<p><strong>Truth is not for cowards.</strong></br></p>
<p><strong>There is a reason why they used emblem of Lotus flower. If you don&rsquo;t have courage to get yourselves dirty, you have no point asking for that Lotus.</strong></br></p>
<p><strong>When you have that fragrance, the world will be a little bit more beautiful.</strong></br></p>
<p><strong>So, Bloom amidst the mud surrounding you</strong> !!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Smiling like a madman</title>
            <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2025/06/smiling-like-a-madman/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2025/06/smiling-like-a-madman/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;First I was innocent,&lt;/br&gt;
I asked for an identity,&lt;/br&gt;
The world pushed me down and pained me.&lt;/br&gt;
I talked to the world about this pain,&lt;/br&gt;
And the world mocked me.&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
I felt alone in this fight,&lt;/br&gt;
I wanted to run away.&lt;/br&gt;
But, she didn&#39;t let me.&lt;/br&gt;
She made me break into a thousand pieces,&lt;/br&gt;
But always took great care that none was lost.&lt;/br&gt;
And when I gave up,&lt;/br&gt;
She made me work on myself.&lt;/br&gt;
And That&#39;s how I recollected myself to be wholler than the whole.&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
-------------------------------xx-------------------------------
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
Second I was in limelight,&lt;/br&gt;
I asked for strength,&lt;/br&gt;
Then the eyes of the world fixated at me pained me.&lt;/br&gt;
Their dreams, their expectations,&lt;/br&gt;
Them trying to fulfill their dreams through me.&lt;/br&gt;
I again talked to the world about the burden of expectations,&lt;/br&gt;
And the world really didn&#39;t care.&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I felt alone again in this fight,&lt;/br&gt;
I wanted to run away.&lt;/br&gt;
But, she didn&#39;t let me.&lt;/br&gt;
She made me take even more burden until I broke again,&lt;/br&gt;
Yet she took great care again that none was lost.&lt;/br&gt;
And when I gave up,&lt;/br&gt;
She made me work on myself.&lt;/br&gt;
And That&#39;s how I recollected myself to be wholler than the whole again.&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
-------------------------------xx-------------------------------
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, I was now strong enough to take any burden.&lt;/br&gt;
I asked for truth,&lt;/br&gt;
I started wandering here and there in search of truth,&lt;/br&gt;
The words from thousand masters buzzed like a bomb inside my head.&lt;/br&gt;
But by now, I knew the world never listened.&lt;/br&gt;
So I chose a few I was hoping would listen without judgement,&lt;/br&gt;
Tried telling them about the never ending search,&lt;/br&gt;
Yet they too didn&amp;rsquo;t get much.&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>First I was innocent,</br>
I asked for an identity,</br>
The world pushed me down and pained me.</br>
I talked to the world about this pain,</br>
And the world mocked me.</br></p>
</br>
I felt alone in this fight,</br>
I wanted to run away.</br>
But, she didn't let me.</br>
She made me break into a thousand pieces,</br>
But always took great care that none was lost.</br>
And when I gave up,</br>
She made me work on myself.</br>
And That's how I recollected myself to be wholler than the whole.</br>
</br>
</br>
-------------------------------xx-------------------------------
</br>
</br>
</br>
Second I was in limelight,</br>
I asked for strength,</br>
Then the eyes of the world fixated at me pained me.</br>
Their dreams, their expectations,</br>
Them trying to fulfill their dreams through me.</br>
I again talked to the world about the burden of expectations,</br>
And the world really didn't care.</br>
<br>
I felt alone again in this fight,</br>
I wanted to run away.</br>
But, she didn't let me.</br>
She made me take even more burden until I broke again,</br>
Yet she took great care again that none was lost.</br>
And when I gave up,</br>
She made me work on myself.</br>
And That's how I recollected myself to be wholler than the whole again.</br>
</br>
</br>
-------------------------------xx-------------------------------
</br>
</br>
</br>
<p>Third, I was now strong enough to take any burden.</br>
I asked for truth,</br>
I started wandering here and there in search of truth,</br>
The words from thousand masters buzzed like a bomb inside my head.</br>
But by now, I knew the world never listened.</br>
So I chose a few I was hoping would listen without judgement,</br>
Tried telling them about the never ending search,</br>
Yet they too didn&rsquo;t get much.</br></p></p>
</br>
</br>
I was feeling utterly alone by then,</br>
I wanted to run away.</br>
But, she didn't let me.</br>
I had to sit there with thousand petals opening inside me,</br>
Yet not even an eye to appreciate.</br>
I wanted to help those few to make it bloom in them,</br>
Yet each one had their own doubts.</br>
</br>
</br>
<p>The petals bloomed, </br>
The petals faded,</br>
And they fell back to the ground.</br>
Forgetting the fact that it is the nature of petals to fall off,</br>
I started crying seeing all those petals within withering away,</br>
Yet she took great care to collect them all for me.</br>
And when I gave up crying,</br>
She held my hand,</br>
She reached out to me with the incense she prepared from those flowers,</br>
And That&rsquo;s how I recollected myself to be wholler than the whole again.</br></p></p>
</br>
</br>
-------------------------------xx-------------------------------
</br>
</br>
</br>
Fourth, I realized myself and my relationship with her.</br>
Through her eyes,</br>
I realized the world too was her all along.</br>
Now, I was no longer bashing my head,</br>
Neither was I trying to make the world understand me.</br>
I was happy with the fragrance she left me with.</br>
</br>
</br>
One day, I realized she had been with me the whole time,</br>
And then,
I no longer needed to run away.</br>
I no longer needed to say anything to the world,</br>
Or hear back something from there.</br>
I no longer was bashing my head.</br>
I was just there lost in the fragrance of the flowers,</br>
And she came.</br>
She asked me to not get lost in that fragrance,</br>
And gave me keys to her garden itself.</br>
</br>
</br>
Now, I sit there smiling like a madman. ☺️ </br>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Dream of Himalayan Yogis</title>
            <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2025/05/dream-of-himalayan-yogis/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2025/05/dream-of-himalayan-yogis/</guid>
            <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dream-of-liberation-from-fear-to-truth&#34;&gt;The Dream of Liberation: From Fear to Truth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wise ones teach that the universe was born from the desire of The One—not out of pity, not to cause pain, but from a longing to multiply and know itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Chhandogya Upanishad (6.2.1) declares,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“sadeva somyedamagra āsīdekamevādvitīyam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;taddhaika āhurasadevedamagra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;āsīdekamevādvitīyaṃ tasmādasataḥ sajjāyata”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—“Somya, before this world was manifest there was only existence, one without a second. On this subject, some maintain that before this world was manifest there was only non-existence, one without a second. Out of that non-existence, existence emerged.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-dream-of-liberation-from-fear-to-truth">The Dream of Liberation: From Fear to Truth</h2>
<p>The wise ones teach that the universe was born from the desire of The One—not out of pity, not to cause pain, but from a longing to multiply and know itself.</p>
<p>As the Chhandogya Upanishad (6.2.1) declares,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“sadeva somyedamagra āsīdekamevādvitīyam</p>
<p>taddhaika āhurasadevedamagra</p>
<p>āsīdekamevādvitīyaṃ tasmādasataḥ sajjāyata”</p>
<p>—“Somya, before this world was manifest there was only existence, one without a second. On this subject, some maintain that before this world was manifest there was only non-existence, one without a second. Out of that non-existence, existence emerged.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Similarly, the Aitareya Upanishad (1.1.1) states,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“om atma va idameka evagra asit nanyat kincana misat sa iksata lokannu srija iti ”</p>
<p>—“OM ! In the beginning this was but the absolute Self alone . There was nothing else whatsoever that winked . It thought , &quot; Let Me create the worlds .&quot; ”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Again, Brihadharanyak Upanishad (1.4.2) says,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Sa va na iva reme,tasmād ekākī na ramate;</p>
<p>sa dvitīya ma icchat&rdquo;</p>
<p>—&ldquo;The One didn&rsquo;t enjoy being solitary. Therefore, the one desired to be two.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>From this primal desire, consciousness split, and the universe exploded into multiplicity. But with this division came pain and suffering, born from the loss of divinity. No longer The One, we became bottles of consciousness—confused, searching, unaware of our origin or destination. What was meant to be a game of enjoyment isn&rsquo;t enjoyment anymore. Yet, as the sages remind us, it’s alright to be confused. The journey back to truth begins with patience. Shakti upasaks and Sufi saints are the prime examples of who can enjoy this duality like no one else. If you understand its a game you chose to play, then it can be fun and exciting for you. But that&rsquo;s a whole another story for another day. Lets just focus on &ldquo;Dream of Liberation&rdquo; for now.</p>
<p>And in that same Brihadaranyak Upanishad, (1.4.1) there is this quote just above this one that goes like this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>sa abibhet</p>
<p>tasmād ekākī bibheti;</p>
<p>sa ha ayam īkṣāṃ cakre,</p>
<p>yat mad anyan nāsti,</p>
<p>kaṣma annu bibhema īti,</p>
<p>tata evāsya bhayaṃ vīyāya,</p>
<p>kasma addhyabheṣyat</p>
<p>dvitīyādvai bhayaṃ bhavati</p>
<p>which means</p>
<p>&ldquo;It was alone and became fearful. Reflecting, it thought, &lsquo;Since there is nothing else but me, what is there to fear?&rsquo; Thus, its fear vanished. For fear arises only from the presence of another.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I hope this clarifies fear, desire and truth as said by the wise ones.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve never met a Himalayan Yogi my entire life. Yet, their idea reached me through multiple books and biographies of such saints. Their vision, I believe, is Spiritual Liberation —a return to unity, to the unconditioned state of being. But there’s a closer dream, a stepping stone: liberation from fear. I&rsquo;d read it somewhere that&rsquo;s their immediate dream. So, I am here to contribute to that dream. This is where my story begins, and where I hope to make a difference.</p>
<h3 id="buddha-s-truth-life-is-suffering">Buddha’s Truth: Life is Suffering</h3>
<p>Lets understand fear and suffering with another lens. A lens that&rsquo;s so sharp and astute. None other than Buddha and his teachings.</p>
<p>When the Buddha attained enlightenment, his first words captured the essence of existence:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Anekajāti samsāram, Sandhāvissam anibbisam, Gahakārakam gavesanto, Dukkhā jāti punappunam”—“Through many a birth in samsara, have I wandered in vain, seeking the builder of this house of life. Repeated birth is indeed suffering.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>He saw the house-builder—the cycle of craving—and declared,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Gahakāraka dittho si, Puna gehaṁ na kāhasi”—“O house-builder, you are seen. You will not build this house again.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>His mind reached the unconditioned, free from desire.</p>
<p>Buddha, a Himalayan Yogi in spirit, revealed the Four Noble Truths, the first being: Life is suffering. Through paths like Hinayana, Mahayana, and Vajrayana, he offered ways to transcend this suffering. Today, Tibetan monks in the Himalayan foothills practice his teachings, meditating in dark caves for years, seeking liberation.</p>
<p>Upon first glance, Buddha&rsquo;s view seems to contradict the idea of desire. But if you have studied Buddhism in little more depth, then you know what created the house in the first place. And that Buddha is indeed talking about &ldquo;Desire&rdquo; that was building the house again and again. Like the wise quote, &ldquo;Truth is One but the explanations are many.&rdquo;</p>
<p>From them, we inherited tools like meditation and yoga—ancient practices, nearly 2,000 years old, designed not to ease our worldly stress but to cut through the illusion of existence and attain nirvana, enlightenment, unity.</p>
<p>Yet, modern practitioners often misunderstand these tools. Yoga’s Eightfold Path—Yama, Niyama, Asana, Pranayama, Pratyahara, Dharana, Dhyana, and Samadhi—is rarely followed in its entirety. Even yoga teachers struggle to grasp its depth. Meditation, too, is often reduced to a quick fix for daily stress, far from its original purpose.
This realization drove me to create something new, rooted in the wisdom of the past but tailored to our present needs.
I&rsquo;m no teacher, but as a keen student, I&rsquo;ve looked deeper than most. Through eight years of meditation, study of Hinduism, Buddhism, stories of Sufi saints, and even Egyptian history, I&rsquo;ve glimpsed the essence of the Yogis’ dream.</p>
<h3 id="my-journey-the-truth-that-transforms">My Journey: The Truth That Transforms</h3>
<p>My transformation began with Vipassana, the meditation technique taught by the Buddha. I had read many scriptures, but I had zero experience of truth.</p>
<p>Two 10-day silent retreats revealed truths that had been invisible, lurking right before my eyes. Then, in a single moment, reality struck me with undeniable force, like lightning, shattering my illusions.</p>
<p>Years later, I realized it wasn’t the silence or the process that transformed me — it was the truth staring me down, impossible to ignore. I fought so hard that when it broke me, the light entered.</p>
<p>Words from scriptures and wise ones became more clearer as I continued meditating.</p>
<p>I’ve seen others attend Vipassana retreats, some even 20 times, yet miss the fundamental lesson. I’ve met those who can quote scriptures fluently but never grasp their essence. My fortune lies in recognizing what truly changed me: not a technique, but the raw encounter with my personal truth. And I want that to happen with you too.</p>
<h3 id="the-vision-an-app-to-face-fear">The Vision: An App to Face Fear</h3>
<p>This insight inspired me to create an app—not for liberation or enlightenment, but for a more immediate goal: to help you face your undeniable truth and liberate yourself from fear. Fear binds us, just as it bound our cave-dwelling ancestors. Despite humanity’s progress—our trust in one another, our interconnected lives sustained by thousands across the globe—we still fear the world. We eat food we don’t grow, wear clothes we don’t make, yet tremble with the same primal anxieties.</p>
<p>This app is a tool to clean your mirror, to reflect your truth clearly. It’s meant to be used and then discarded, like a ladder climbed and left behind. It won’t grant spiritual liberation, but it will take you to the first step: a world where fear no longer drives you. Generations have survived wars, brutality, and chaos, yet we’ve grown together, trusted, and thrived. This app will remind you of that resilience, showing you a world there&rsquo;s not much to fear. Most of your anxieties comes from your caveman survival instinct deeply coded onto your genes.</p>
<h3 id="unlocking-infinite-potential">Unlocking Infinite Potential</h3>
<p>You sit atop infinite potential, bound only by fear. My mission is to help you unlock it. This journey may take years, even decades, but with true effort, you’ll be able to find your personal truth. You will finally live like royalty—free to meditate, to create, to arrive at the world awaiting you. Until your mirror is clean, you cannot comprehend what lies ahead.</p>
<p>The Himalayan Yogis dreamed of spiritual liberation, but their closer dream—freedom from fear—is within our reach. This app is my offering to that vision, a bridge to a fearless world. Let’s eliminate fear first. Then, together, we’ll see what comes next.</p>
<p>I had the idea almost two years ago. I am sorry for taking this long to build this. Finally as AI got better, it helped my development path quiet a lot. This is not a sales pitch because I don&rsquo;t expect anything from you except that you someday arrive at that place where I arrived some years ago.</p>
<p><strong>No data collection, no ads, no money to pay.</strong></p>
<p>Locked to only you so that you can record deepest darkest thoughts without worrying a bit. Just use it so that one day you can throw it away. I might add feature to share your stories to one another for moral boost someday. Until then, its not even connecting to the internet.</p>
<p><strong>Only thing that it requires is your attention to your life: observing the patterns of your mind until you&rsquo;re free from it.</strong></p>
<p>This is my personal motivation and my dream behind creating this project.</p>
<p>More tools will come at <a href="https://maitreyatools.com">https://maitreyatools.com</a>.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>2024 in a nutshell</title>
            <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2024/12/2024-in-a-nutshell/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2024/12/2024-in-a-nutshell/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;I started this year differently compared to years before. In the year&amp;rsquo;s end, I saw who I could become, who I was and got some glimpse into what 2024 was going to be about. Really got energized already at the start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2023 was speeding with insights. Its been a slow year compared to 2023 because everything was about calming down. We built a home for ourselves. I realized having a home that you design and build yourself based on how you want it to look like and make you feel, is a great blessing. Its been one wholesome journey to build my home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started this year differently compared to years before. In the year&rsquo;s end, I saw who I could become, who I was and got some glimpse into what 2024 was going to be about. Really got energized already at the start.</p>
<p>2023 was speeding with insights. Its been a slow year compared to 2023 because everything was about calming down. We built a home for ourselves. I realized having a home that you design and build yourself based on how you want it to look like and make you feel, is a great blessing. Its been one wholesome journey to build my home.</p>
<p>Completed watching One Piece this year. The theme, the friendship, the adventure all really engulfed me to feel like I am one of them. Such a joy. This year I watched two more animes: Jujitsu Kaizen ( Fight scenes were animated so good that I enjoyed fight scenes for the very first time in movies/animes ), and Demon Slayer ( Enjoyed watching it but nothing very specific to say about it).</p>
<p>In the process, one instance where I over-analyzed One Piece awakening to enlightenment and creation:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>One question I had for a long time was whether I wanted enlightenment or creation. That answer came today. Enlightenment is like having infinite observation haki as well as zoan type devil fruit that has will of it&rsquo;s own. Once its awakened, its will is yours and yours is its will. So, the way I am going to balance is similar to how devil fruits awakening gets balanced. You don&rsquo;t always awaken it but only when needed.
That way you can have it your way.
&ndash; 2024-02-17</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Who knows, maybe I will have my way. Its a contradiction in itself and nothing really comes out of pondering on it. If it happens, I will know. Until it happens, its a play of my mind. Taking rest right there. 😁</p>
<p>Next thing I got this year is understanding of role of Divine Feminine in all of creation and enlightenment. It was always clear to me about the creative aspect of it but I hadn&rsquo;t gone very deep into it. The more I have learned of divine feminine and her presence in my life, I have been more clear and clear about what I need. I realized I was getting everything I need without even asking for it. Its happening step by step weirdly, and I am excited to see on which note 2025 ends in.</p>
<p>While saying this, its really essential to understand the difference between <em>not acting at all vs acting without tying yourself to the fruits of it</em>. I have always wanted to be <strong>autotelic</strong> and in that process, there is no place for thought about outcome while at it. I enjoy it, and that&rsquo;s the outcome. I do plan, I do act accordingly. I use my cognitive ability to come up with improved solutions, but I don&rsquo;t tie myself to any act or its output. This is the basics of &ldquo;Karma Yog&rdquo; of Bhagvad Geeta. You will always know what you need to do and do it. If you know you aren&rsquo;t doing something to avoid boredom, that&rsquo;s enough information to know. Rest will fall in place.</p>
<p>There have been pointers that have blown my mind this year. I don&rsquo;t know if they are real or not, but I know if they are real, they demand my 100 percent on it. 2025 will be about verifying those pointers as well. It will end in either of two ways I will live my life. I have one of these two ways to live my life:</p>
<ol>
<li>Live a life of a monk. Accepting everything as is and not really owning anything. Knowing its all ephemeral and will end.</li>
<li>Live a life of a king. Knowing that everything is yours but if everything is yours, there is nothing that you need to possess because its already yours.</li>
</ol>
<p>A drawing of what creation/enlightenment seems to be explained like:
<img src="/ox-hugo/GX0eObeakAENy89.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>2025 will decide what life I am going to live. Therefore for 2025, I have set my theme color as <strong>purple/violet</strong> ( the color of the sahasrara ) 🟣🔮🟪 .</p>
<p>This year, for the first time in my life, I visited museums and art galleries. I used to read about art, renaissance, history but never put in time to just enjoy these in real life.
I moved from one place to another multiple times finally ending my stay in the valley temporarily after 11 years, starting a new phase.</p>
<p>I always try to read a decent number of books. I don&rsquo;t decide which books I read. I put a lot of books on my boox device and just let the mood decide which I read/complete. Timing chooses books. Some get completed, some don&rsquo;t. Sometimes I just reading 20% of a book and move to the next. Sometimes, I come back to it again and again, only to read few pages and move to the next. But overall, reading has been one of my favorite pastimes. A big credit of who I am today is to the books that have found me. Hope amazing books find you too in 2025.</p>
<h2 id="books-re-read">Books re-read</h2>
<ul>
<li>The Creative Act : A way of Being by Rick Rubin ( This book is such a masterpiece of creating art. I think it will be valuable as people will try to find identity in a world where AI will start doing most of the tasks that we have been doing. )</li>
<li>Facebook&rsquo;s Little Red Book ( This is such a clear book of theme, vision and why values matter. Inspiration always wins. Each page is a beauty. I need a physical copy now. )</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="completed-this-year">Completed This year</h2>
<ul>
<li>Breath: The New Science of a Lost Art ( The activity that we do the most frequent in our lives needed to be at least understood. Though I haven&rsquo;t deeply pursued each findings present in the book, I understand not to breath via mouth except for relaxation. And I agree that increasing VO2 max (a.k.a. lung capacity) is a good indicator for overall longevity. )</li>
<li>The Root Stanzas of the Middle Way: The Mulamadhyamkarika by Nagarjuna ( This is a masterpiece of Mahayana Tradition of Buddhism. It took some time to go into details and understand it but the philosophical treatise is something that will keep me pondering over and over. Really good guide on what exactly is emptiness. Its contradictions seem ironical, but if you have experienced something along the way, it fits right in the middle like the title suggests. )</li>
<li>Pride and Prejudice ( First fiction I read this year. Its always refreshing to read books that have happy ending. LOL 🤭 One thing I have realized is human emotions have always remained the same throughout time. Feels like just the clothes and environment has changed. Like you can play same game with different background. Made me realize how unique we think of ourselves but in the end the emotional body is very close to many who have already lived and died. )</li>
<li>The Picture of Dorian Gray ( Such a beautiful book. Such good philosophy sprinkled over like salt over good food. Title having name Gray suits it. Grayness of morality clarified in a intricate manner)</li>
<li>The Importance of Being Earnest ( A humorous read )</li>
<li>Living with the Himalayan Masters by Swami Rama ( Swami Rama is a sage who taught many breathing techniques to the west and also tried doing experiments to show what he can do by controlling breathing like controlling heart rate, temperature etc. but much of that remains to debate now. Got to know him from book on Breath. )</li>
<li>Love Whispers ( After reading Swami Rama&rsquo;s autobiography, wanted to learn more about him. This is collection of excerpts from his diary where he shares his intimate relationship with Divine Feminine.)</li>
<li>Atmamun by Kapil Gupta ( Live life like a monk or like a king. Find your way and live it. This has helped me corroborate what I had felt like as to how to live my life. I know how much I can know, how much I need to know, and not be troubled by what I don&rsquo;t know or wouldn&rsquo;t know in this lifetime. So, I am going to live. )</li>
<li>The Joy of Abstraction by Eugenia Cheng ( Completed this to get a good enough understanding of category theory because Bartosz&rsquo;s Category Theory book wasn&rsquo;t clearing all my doubts. She had a good video about it, so I read it. Book is good for a basic understanding. )</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="in-progress">In Progress</h2>
<ul>
<li>I am That by Nisargadatta Maharaj ( Clarifies a lot of philosophical discussions around enlightenment and being in general, half way through )</li>
<li>Category Theory for Programmers by Bartosz ( Completed the basic chapters, now on to intermediate )</li>
<li>Essential Rumi ( Getting to know his life and poems, this man is something else if you talk of love )</li>
<li>Professor Frisby&rsquo;s Mostly Adequate Guide to Functional Programming ( Got the basics, practiced some, but haven&rsquo;t completed it)</li>
<li>Catch 22 ( Re-read upto some chapters only to get stalled again, this book doesn&rsquo;t want to be read for some weird reason 😝 )</li>
<li>The Beginning of Infinity ( Close to completing it this time. Such an amazing book. The concepts to which he concludes coming from a whole different perspective is something else. It became a lot like my revisit to Philosophy, Quantum Mechanics, and Optimism. )</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="notes">Notes</h2>
<ul>
<li>Reading about spirituality is one thing, experiencing it is another.</li>
<li>Its ironical that people have been forcing meditation. Its something that you have to have discipline about but that discipline should be limited to your body. You cannot tame your mind in the same way you tame your body. Only way out is to watch where the mind goes with sharp-pointedness that the mind sees the futility of its moving. Your mind always knows the tricks you try to play with it and always will outsmart you. Who even is you, if not the mind right now? So, just watch. Don&rsquo;t care whoever is watching and whoever is being watched. The patterns unravel themselves right before you when you don&rsquo;t try, when you don&rsquo;t force to bring something to the surface.</li>
<li>I am reading more and more about Himalayan sages, Tantra and knowing more about the enlightened masters.</li>
<li>I have been very curious about my heritage, who my ancestors have been, why they did what they did, and if there&rsquo;s something to be learned about. And I have come across a few things that we have lost through our generations. There are rabbit holes wherever you try to pursue.</li>
<li>Category Theory has felt harder to unravel for me but nonetheless beautiful. I have yet to understand the beauty of structure that it provides, but I am hopeful in the process.</li>
<li>The progress that has been made on AI seems awesome. I am looking forward to what we will see in our lifetimes with optimism.</li>
<li>I predicted a 10 year prediction this year to understand myself as well as the world better. <a href="https://x.com/_aloki/status/1847607326036922409">https://x.com/_aloki/status/1847607326036922409</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Ending this with the poem from Dylan Thomas:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Do not go gentle into that good night,</p>
<p>Old age should burn and rave at close of day;</p>
<p>Rage, rage against the dying of the light.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>On Love</title>
            <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2023/10/on-love/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2023/10/on-love/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been trying to write some essays on basic words that are the hardest to capture because often times it&amp;rsquo;s these words that stir up conflict: love, happiness, fulfillment, peace, pain, god,  spirituality etc.
Because they are the most overused, yet least understood by our subconscious minds, our subconscious gets trippy while making sense.
I started writing this essay about six months ago.  In trying to write this essay, I started by searching for word love in my personal notes vault. It got overwhelming even after a day digesting, that I gave up the pursuit for some time. I really didn&amp;rsquo;t have any digest apart from notes and excerpts from others. I knew where to start, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t end it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been trying to write some essays on basic words that are the hardest to capture because often times it&rsquo;s these words that stir up conflict: love, happiness, fulfillment, peace, pain, god,  spirituality etc.
Because they are the most overused, yet least understood by our subconscious minds, our subconscious gets trippy while making sense.
I started writing this essay about six months ago.  In trying to write this essay, I started by searching for word love in my personal notes vault. It got overwhelming even after a day digesting, that I gave up the pursuit for some time. I really didn&rsquo;t have any digest apart from notes and excerpts from others. I knew where to start, but couldn&rsquo;t end it.</p>
<p>This is where I start. Where is love word used often? Whenever anyone feels like there is an intensity of anything, they call it love.
Examples:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Desire</strong> : Love for ownership</li>
<li><strong>Passion</strong> : Love for fulfillment</li>
<li><strong>Sex</strong> : Love for pleasure</li>
<li><strong>Flow</strong> : Love for work</li>
</ul>
<p>etc.
If love is just intensity at its peak, why is love praised that much? Can you call intense greed as love for greed? If not, why do you call high intensity to cause violence as <strong>love for violence</strong>. If it can be used on any connotation, is there really anything praiseworthy about it?
e.g.</p>
<p><strong>Paulo Coelho in The Alchemist</strong> says maybe love simply is nourishment and compares love to a falcon&rsquo;s flight over the sand being definition of love given by the desert. The desert reasons that falcon carries bits of itself, and feeds the falcon little water that it has right there; thus the nourishment.</p>
<p><strong>Lao Tzu in Tao Te Ching</strong> talks about love without imposing the will, love as a leader, love as a mystery, and posits a spiritual question. &ldquo;Is greatest love indifferent?&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Gabriel Gracia Marquez in One Hundred Years of Solitude</strong> shows how you see love everywhere, how passion and love interchangably entangle, whether we can be exhausted of love, and whether two solitary people can be in love.
Charles Bukwoski has a book titled &ldquo;Love is a dog from hell.&rdquo;</p>
<p>There will be thousand more references to word love if you google it. I deferred this essay and  had been trying to answer other questions related to fear and death instead for last year. All of a sudden, both the answers came at the same time. Finally, I had an essay I wanted to share.</p>
<p>I want to make note of what&rsquo;s easiest about describing love. Love with a person. Though I start with romantic love, the conclusion applies to any love. Love with a person, thing, God, or anything.
I will start with loving someone as I have come to know it. I have been close with a few people emotionally. Had multitudes of experience from love at first sight ( in people&rsquo;s words ) to being in a relationship. I have connected with someone on a purely intellectual level where we had so much topics in common that we talked for hours on end, and never get tired. I have been emotionally involved with someone who matched most of my interests. It was fun to talk to and hangout with that someone. I thought I was at least in love when I was with someone in a relationship, in possessing someone whom I called mine. At that time I thought life was about one love and I believed it to be love for a very long time. Then I liked someone, wanted to be with them, but never really feeling like being with them. At some point, I saw love in trying to emapthize for someone. There were few days where situation would make it feel like a perfect match but that was pleasure misinterpreted as love.</p>
<p>What people call love at first sight was all hormones piling up to give one of the most pleasurable experiences, but not really love. On my first ever love at first sight, I really felt music buzz my ears, stomach curled up when I saw her. I was sure she was an angel that evening. But hormones fade, as fast as they pile up. That&rsquo;s what love at first sight is. It&rsquo;s a biological response of you liking someone because nature wants you to breed.</p>
<p>Being intimate emotionally and intellectually with someone is freedom, one degree close to love than even that pleasure where you had a crush. You put down your guards. It&rsquo;s not overwhelming like the first one, but much more relieving. A crush moment is instantaneous, but intimacy lasts.</p>
<p>Being in a relationship came as a whole different story. They are already as important as your family, and when you have accepted their most vices as inconsequential is even more closer to love than anything else. This is what I thought was love till the moment because that was all that I had experienced. You possess them as yours. You feel safe with them. Most of the feeling comes from not having an emotional void to express with someone when in a relationship.</p>
<p>I thought that was all there is. Thus, I believed the highest attainment is love where two people are in a relationship, like each other, and spend their lives together. They are individuals, but they like spending their life together rather than all alone.</p>
<p>Then came my final experience, which needed me to redefine what I had known so far.
This is love where I experienced this wierdness that I had a difficult time finding words to describe.</p>
<p>Lets start with a context first.</p>
<p>I had crush on someone for some time. I got to talking with that someone, meeting them too. At that time, I was trying to see as many people as I can, in a hope to understand my preferences better. That someone didn&rsquo;t want to take it forward, so I left that situation the best I can. I was dating other people, but very briefly. I got stuck on that someone emotionally.</p>
<p>I was still unsure whether I wanted to be with them because I couldn&rsquo;t take this in a normal pace. I was already thinking long term without knowing them enough. And making decisions quickly on emotional matters is not my forte. I tried hard to move away from them, dated a few other people, but still stuck.</p>
<p>I had one doubt about that person being the right match, that&rsquo;s why I never went all in. One day while reading a book, I came to an understanding that opened that barrier for me.
It had been an year or so since I had last talked. I decided to take a chance and take it as it goes even if it ends up hurting me. I called to meet and that someone agreed.</p>
<p>First I was happy, then I was anxious. I almost had forgotten how anxiety felt like because I was experiencing any sort of anxiety after almost a year. To give you context, I have been meditating for years now, and am rarely anxious. That day, I couldn&rsquo;t sleep and decided to meditate.</p>
<p>Meditation is where my inner lake gets calm. Half an hour into that, I realized anxiety arises from desire, not from love. I still meditated. There is a practice called &ldquo;Metta&rdquo; ( Good will and Gratitude Practice ) that&rsquo;s done at the end of Vipassana meditation practice. It usually is done for the last five minutes, but I decided to do it amidst my one hour practice that day. Also, I decided to do Metta just for that someone. In that practice of radiating love, after 10 minutes or so, my desire slowly faded away. Voila!! There was no anxiety.</p>
<p>I was peaceful, full of love, and cheerful. It felt so fucking weird that I couldn&rsquo;t make sense of it. It didn&rsquo;t last very long, about an hour or so after I woke from meditation. But at that moment, I felt blissed like I had never been before. The weiredest part is that I was unafraid of even death. It felt like even if someone stabbed me in that moment, I would die peacefully with a smile on my face. There was one more catch to it: I had always heard about how ego is the final barrier in spiritual path, to which I realized I had no ego that whole time. Not even a tinge of it. I was ready to give anything and everything up cheerfully.</p>
<p>I had been reading and meditating on death and fear for almost an year now in trying to overcome it. I had built a decent enough understanding about the topics, but not really nailed it. I was still seeking for an answer. I had no idea that my answer would come this way.</p>
<p>Even when that someone decided lastly that they didn&rsquo;t want to meet me, there was pain. But I didn&rsquo;t want that pain to subside. I remained aware and calm through it. I wanted to feel everything in its fullest depth. My logical mind couldn&rsquo;t  make sense because that was not how people I saw dealt with heartbreak neither in real life nor in movies. I wanted to just feel everything without diverting it by movies, songs, drinking, or activity of any sort. Seeing this, my mind created a doubt as to whether I really was in love or I was just faking myself. Only because that experience was way too vivid and absorbing, denying that didn&rsquo;t come easy.</p>
<p>Days passed and I still couldn&rsquo;t  believe what happened.
Over a period of a month, I came across some references that described what I felt. I stumbled across couple more references, and then I finally found my answer as to what happened.</p>
<p>First is a story told by Osho:
One day desire and knowledge met with Ganga. Ganga told both of them that she would purify them. Knowledge didn&rsquo;t go but desire did. When desired came purified out of the river, it&rsquo;d became love.</p>
<p>I found few Rumi&rsquo;s quotes:</p>
<ul>
<li>From understading comes love.</li>
<li>Exhale only love.</li>
<li>Close your eyes, fall in love, stay there.</li>
<li>You have within you more love than you could ever understand.</li>
<li>Your task is not to seek for love, but merely to seek and find all the barriers within yourself that you have built against it.</li>
</ul>
<p>This guy was in love like no one else. I felt connection to these lines immediately after seeing one. It would have been impossible for me to express it, had it not been this guy who had said it already. My experience would have been lost to my logic and memory had I not found his lines.</p>
<p>Finally, it does not like a hallucination or a dream I created. Though that state lasted only an hour or so, that was real. That was how Rumi loved The Godhead. That&rsquo;s what love as in love is. Everything else is love added with something: sometimes with desire, sometimes with pleasure, sometimes with work, sometimes with passion etc.</p>
<p>Experiences and insights from meditation rarely last long. It takes one moment to see the door, but years more to absorb it into day-to-day life. I am grateful that I got a rare glimpse.</p>
<p><strong>This is my essay &ldquo;On Love&rdquo;.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Turning a quarter old</title>
            <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2023/09/turning-a-quarter-old/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 17:05:00 +0545</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2023/09/turning-a-quarter-old/</guid>
            <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;books-read-this-year&#34;&gt;Books read this year&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brave New World&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One Hundred Years of Solitude&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Twilight Saga [ 1-4 ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to Read a Book&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What would you do if you weren&amp;rsquo;t afraid?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turiya - The God State: Beyond Kundalini, Kriya Yoga &amp;amp; all Spirituality (Real Yoga)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How Psychology Works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being You: A New Science of Consciousness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to find love&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make something wonderful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;American Gods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tibetan Book of Living and Dying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logicomix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Phoenix Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Art of Dying by Osho&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Old Man and the sea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zen Mind Beginners Mind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Isa Upanishad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chhandogya Upanishad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enlightenment is your nature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;101 Essays That Will Change the Way You Think&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;books-in-progress&#34;&gt;Books In Progress:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;remnants-from-last-year&#34;&gt;Remnants from Last Year&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dhando Investor [ Not in that mental state of value investing rn ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lives of the Stoics [ Got enough philosophy to be useful ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meditations by Marcus Aurelius [ Same with meditations ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code Breaker by Walter Issacson [ Excited upto the point of decision for a Nobel Prize. Felt like that was all I needed ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Krishnamurti&amp;rsquo;s Notebooks [ Needs absorption rather than completion ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dream Yourself Awake [ Practice is more important. Only after mastering certain techniques, I will move forward ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Monk who sold his Ferrari [ Started re-reading but dropped it ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;newly-added&#34;&gt;Newly added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love Her Wild&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Sun and her flowers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Milk and Honey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zen and The Art of Motorcycle Maintenance [ Too much zen already :P ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indian Philosophy [ It&amp;rsquo;s a big one. So much information, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to just process ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Book of Secrets by Osho [ About techniques, no point in finishing the book ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mulamadhyamkarika: Wisdom of the Middle Way by Nagarjuna [ Really intrigued by first chapter but cannot get time to contemplate on the ideas, pretty complex ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oxford Handbook on Philosophy of Death [ Philosophy needs decent time to digest through introspection and speculation, which I currently don&amp;rsquo;t have ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Head First Design Patterns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Little Book about OS Development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The God Delusion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Godel Escher Bach: An Eternal Golden Braid [ Really beautiful ideas which I really want to absorb, rather than read ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salt, Fat, Acid, Heat: A Science of Cooking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Beginning of Infinity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Design of Everyday Things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lokpriya Sayar aur Unki Sayari&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Catch 22&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I read word &amp;ldquo;Bardo&amp;rdquo; for the first time in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Godel Escher Bach: An Eternal Golden Braid&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. When I read &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Tibetan Book of Dying and Living&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, I found out that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bardo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was a Tibetan word taken into English, and has a very big significance in Tibetan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tibetans are very clear about stages after death, re-incarnation, enlightenment on par with our clarity about daily tasks we do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The more I read about neuroscience, the more I love reading philosophy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Sanskrit and Sanskrit Texts:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sanskrit Grammar is such an elegant topic that was written a long time ago. I have no problem with people rejecting anything, but if we have no appreciation for the roots that we gave to the world, we are losing our identity into it. Sanskrit Grammar is one of the first complete grammar of any language in the world. Very elaborate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am more intrigued by Eastern Philosophy because it&amp;rsquo;s easy to understand, easy because it fills gaps from our traditions, other related stories like Puranas, and folklores. Since Nepali language is derived from Sanskrit as well, I can contemplate some ideas from Sanskrit into my mind directly too. I have at least learned primitive level Sanskrit Grammar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most of the Buddhist texts were originally written in Sanskrit and Pali. Still to this day, Tibetans read both Sanskrit and Tibetan translation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Nepal and India, we see Hinduism as this giant ball of tradition. We, as intellectuals, need to be able to separate contemporary usefulness of traditions from philosophy, and give it a fair chance without making it a mockery by comparing it with Western Philosophy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upanishads are the lesser known beautiful extracts of Hindu tradition that comes under &lt;strong&gt;Vedanta&lt;/strong&gt;. Upanishads are called &lt;strong&gt;Vedanta&lt;/strong&gt; [ The End of Vedas ] because it&amp;rsquo;s said that they contain all the teachings of Veda in a more succinct form. Philosophical foods of thought that have been neglected because it&amp;rsquo;s hard to make philosophy a part of tradition unlike stories ( a.k.a Puranas ). There are many Upanishads, but 108 principal ones. Among them, 9 or 11 are said to be of significant importance. They are just like a few poems long.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make Something Wonderful by Steve Jobs is a simple yet beautiful book on how Steve&amp;rsquo;s mind worked. And, it really is inspiring for someone who wants to build stuff for people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every school should teach &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Read a Book&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Reading is not just memorizing or marking something as complete. Reading is much more. And it depends on what you are reading. You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t read everything the same way. Like Francis Bacon said, &amp;ldquo;Some books are to be tasted, others to be swallowed, and some few to be chewed and digested.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s easier said than done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having a kindle really helps me because I can pick and drop books at any time without feeling guilty about it. I usually have around 200 books on my kindle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are curious about getting overview and some details into theory of consciousness, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Being You&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by Anil Seth is a great book. I loved his talks through the years, and this is a good digest of the whole field of consciousness and his theory of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read Psychology so you can understand your mind better. Reading Psychology + Meditating helps me clarify a lot of my confusions, and helps me accept conclusions that I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like accepting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have been pretty intrigued by death for a year or two now because I see it as hindrance to my true fulfillment. How can I truly be if I am always running away from something invisible? I still have amends to make, but a lot of ideas have been still like a lake on my mind. It&amp;rsquo;s not that the waves don&amp;rsquo;t come, but they settle quickly. I hope to be in equanimity with death soon enough, so that I can truly live.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zen is nothing more nothing less than mindfulness. There can be a thousand teachings and koans, but the essence is to simply be. The closest example of Zen that you can understand is Kung Fu Panda. Compare Master Shifu, Po, and Master Oogway; right in that comparison is answer to what Zen is. Knowing is one thing; accepting is another which you can learn from Shifu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am really loving &lt;strong&gt;Godel Escher Bach: An Eternal Golden Braid&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any recommendations, or want certain recommendations; hit me up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="books-read-this-year">Books read this year</h2>
<ul>
<li>Brave New World</li>
<li>One Hundred Years of Solitude</li>
<li>The Twilight Saga [ 1-4 ]</li>
<li>How to Read a Book</li>
<li>What would you do if you weren&rsquo;t afraid?</li>
<li>Turiya - The God State: Beyond Kundalini, Kriya Yoga &amp; all Spirituality (Real Yoga)</li>
<li>How Psychology Works</li>
<li>Being You: A New Science of Consciousness</li>
<li>How to find love</li>
<li>Make something wonderful</li>
<li>American Gods</li>
<li>The Tibetan Book of Living and Dying</li>
<li>Logicomix</li>
<li>The Phoenix Project</li>
<li>The Art of Dying by Osho</li>
<li>The Old Man and the sea</li>
<li>Zen Mind Beginners Mind</li>
<li>Isa Upanishad</li>
<li>Chhandogya Upanishad</li>
<li>Enlightenment is your nature</li>
<li>101 Essays That Will Change the Way You Think</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="books-in-progress">Books In Progress:</h2>
<h3 id="remnants-from-last-year">Remnants from Last Year</h3>
<ul>
<li>Dhando Investor [ Not in that mental state of value investing rn ]</li>
<li>Lives of the Stoics [ Got enough philosophy to be useful ]</li>
<li>Meditations by Marcus Aurelius [ Same with meditations ]</li>
<li>Code Breaker by Walter Issacson [ Excited upto the point of decision for a Nobel Prize. Felt like that was all I needed ]</li>
<li>Krishnamurti&rsquo;s Notebooks [ Needs absorption rather than completion ]</li>
<li>Dream Yourself Awake [ Practice is more important. Only after mastering certain techniques, I will move forward ]</li>
<li>The Monk who sold his Ferrari [ Started re-reading but dropped it ]</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="newly-added">Newly added</h3>
<ul>
<li>Love Her Wild</li>
<li>The Sun and her flowers</li>
<li>Milk and Honey</li>
<li>Zen and The Art of Motorcycle Maintenance [ Too much zen already :P ]</li>
<li>Indian Philosophy [ It&rsquo;s a big one. So much information, it&rsquo;s hard to just process ]</li>
<li>The Book of Secrets by Osho [ About techniques, no point in finishing the book ]</li>
<li>Mulamadhyamkarika: Wisdom of the Middle Way by Nagarjuna [ Really intrigued by first chapter but cannot get time to contemplate on the ideas, pretty complex ]</li>
<li>Oxford Handbook on Philosophy of Death [ Philosophy needs decent time to digest through introspection and speculation, which I currently don&rsquo;t have ]</li>
<li>Head First Design Patterns</li>
<li>The Little Book about OS Development</li>
<li>The God Delusion</li>
<li>Godel Escher Bach: An Eternal Golden Braid [ Really beautiful ideas which I really want to absorb, rather than read ]</li>
<li>Salt, Fat, Acid, Heat: A Science of Cooking</li>
<li>The Beginning of Infinity</li>
<li>The Design of Everyday Things</li>
<li>Lokpriya Sayar aur Unki Sayari</li>
<li>Catch 22</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="notes">Notes</h2>
<ul>
<li>I read word &ldquo;Bardo&rdquo; for the first time in <strong><strong>Godel Escher Bach: An Eternal Golden Braid</strong></strong>. When I read <strong><strong>The Tibetan Book of Dying and Living</strong></strong>, I found out that <strong><strong>Bardo</strong></strong> was a Tibetan word taken into English, and has a very big significance in Tibetan.</li>
<li>Tibetans are very clear about stages after death, re-incarnation, enlightenment on par with our clarity about daily tasks we do.</li>
<li>The more I read about neuroscience, the more I love reading philosophy.</li>
<li>On Sanskrit and Sanskrit Texts:
<ul>
<li>Sanskrit Grammar is such an elegant topic that was written a long time ago. I have no problem with people rejecting anything, but if we have no appreciation for the roots that we gave to the world, we are losing our identity into it. Sanskrit Grammar is one of the first complete grammar of any language in the world. Very elaborate.</li>
<li>I am more intrigued by Eastern Philosophy because it&rsquo;s easy to understand, easy because it fills gaps from our traditions, other related stories like Puranas, and folklores. Since Nepali language is derived from Sanskrit as well, I can contemplate some ideas from Sanskrit into my mind directly too. I have at least learned primitive level Sanskrit Grammar.</li>
<li>Most of the Buddhist texts were originally written in Sanskrit and Pali. Still to this day, Tibetans read both Sanskrit and Tibetan translation.</li>
<li>In Nepal and India, we see Hinduism as this giant ball of tradition. We, as intellectuals, need to be able to separate contemporary usefulness of traditions from philosophy, and give it a fair chance without making it a mockery by comparing it with Western Philosophy.</li>
<li>Upanishads are the lesser known beautiful extracts of Hindu tradition that comes under <strong>Vedanta</strong>. Upanishads are called <strong>Vedanta</strong> [ The End of Vedas ] because it&rsquo;s said that they contain all the teachings of Veda in a more succinct form. Philosophical foods of thought that have been neglected because it&rsquo;s hard to make philosophy a part of tradition unlike stories ( a.k.a Puranas ). There are many Upanishads, but 108 principal ones. Among them, 9 or 11 are said to be of significant importance. They are just like a few poems long.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Make Something Wonderful by Steve Jobs is a simple yet beautiful book on how Steve&rsquo;s mind worked. And, it really is inspiring for someone who wants to build stuff for people.</li>
<li>Every school should teach <strong><strong>How to Read a Book</strong></strong>. Reading is not just memorizing or marking something as complete. Reading is much more. And it depends on what you are reading. You shouldn&rsquo;t read everything the same way. Like Francis Bacon said, &ldquo;Some books are to be tasted, others to be swallowed, and some few to be chewed and digested.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s easier said than done.</li>
<li>Having a kindle really helps me because I can pick and drop books at any time without feeling guilty about it. I usually have around 200 books on my kindle.</li>
<li>If you are curious about getting overview and some details into theory of consciousness, <strong><strong>Being You</strong></strong> by Anil Seth is a great book. I loved his talks through the years, and this is a good digest of the whole field of consciousness and his theory of it.</li>
<li>Read Psychology so you can understand your mind better. Reading Psychology + Meditating helps me clarify a lot of my confusions, and helps me accept conclusions that I don&rsquo;t feel like accepting.</li>
<li>I have been pretty intrigued by death for a year or two now because I see it as hindrance to my true fulfillment. How can I truly be if I am always running away from something invisible? I still have amends to make, but a lot of ideas have been still like a lake on my mind. It&rsquo;s not that the waves don&rsquo;t come, but they settle quickly. I hope to be in equanimity with death soon enough, so that I can truly live.</li>
<li>Zen is nothing more nothing less than mindfulness. There can be a thousand teachings and koans, but the essence is to simply be. The closest example of Zen that you can understand is Kung Fu Panda. Compare Master Shifu, Po, and Master Oogway; right in that comparison is answer to what Zen is. Knowing is one thing; accepting is another which you can learn from Shifu.</li>
<li>I am really loving <strong>Godel Escher Bach: An Eternal Golden Braid</strong>.</li>
</ul>
<p>If you have any recommendations, or want certain recommendations; hit me up.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My relationship with my body</title>
            <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2023/01/my-relationship-with-my-body/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2023/01/my-relationship-with-my-body/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;We all identify our bodies as &amp;ldquo;my body&amp;rdquo; and &lt;strong&gt;not me directly&lt;/strong&gt;. The whole idea of this blog post revolves around this idea. The purpose of this blog post is to establish an idea on how to build healthier lifestyle based on this concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not like we intentionally don&amp;rsquo;t want to build healthier habits. We try to pick up exercise habits, but we are too lazy to work on it. We eat haphazardly, and without any consideration to our health. It&amp;rsquo;s a very universal problem. So, I had the same problem. On top of that, I have always been a person low in Conscientiousness, which means I used to have a hard time pushing my goals to myself if I was the only one responsible for it. Finally, I found a way that worked for me that might work for you too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We all identify our bodies as &ldquo;my body&rdquo; and <strong>not me directly</strong>. The whole idea of this blog post revolves around this idea. The purpose of this blog post is to establish an idea on how to build healthier lifestyle based on this concept.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s not like we intentionally don&rsquo;t want to build healthier habits. We try to pick up exercise habits, but we are too lazy to work on it. We eat haphazardly, and without any consideration to our health. It&rsquo;s a very universal problem. So, I had the same problem. On top of that, I have always been a person low in Conscientiousness, which means I used to have a hard time pushing my goals to myself if I was the only one responsible for it. Finally, I found a way that worked for me that might work for you too.</p>
<p>So, the main idea is this:
Instead of thinking of my body as me (same identity), I changed the scenario by treating &ldquo;my body&rdquo; as being separate from &ldquo;me&rdquo;. Now, There are two players in the game.
Player 1 : Me[ My emotions, cravings, feelings ]
Player 2 : My body [ Physical body ]
Both of whom are playing an optimization game to favor themselves.</p>
<p>My body communicates via muscle signals, dis-ease, etc. My thoughts are self-evident.</p>
<p>For me, the game started looking like a zero-sum optimization game at the beginning. e.g. Either I was taking care of my health or I was fulfilling my cravings, and feel-good emotions. But as I came to understand intentions of both players [ my body and me ] with more clarity, the same game resurfaced as a positive-sum game. This change of the game itself happened as my perspective on what I was optimizing for aligned with what my body wanted to optimize. In simpler terms, I&rsquo;d thought building healthy habits would be boring which turned out to be a false proposition.</p>
<p>I started by clarifying the goals of each player in this optimization game. Each goal has time to feedback as well as importance of feedback. Based on a weighted sum of feedback, based on time as well as importance, the decision&rsquo;s made. Initially, the goals and their characteristics looked as follows:</p>
<h2 id="goal-for-agent-1--me">Goal for agent 1 ( me )</h2>
<ol>
<li>Tastes good : Immediate feedback, High importance to feedback.</li>
<li>Feels good ( e.g. Drinking alcohol in other&rsquo;s company though it doesn&rsquo;t taste good ): Immediate feedback, High importance to feedback.</li>
<li>Avoid any physical pain : No immediate feedback since punishment&rsquo;s delayed in time. Low importance to feedback. ( e.g. I don&rsquo;t immediately get obese. )</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="goal-for-agent-2--my-body">Goal for agent 2 ( my body )</h2>
<ol>
<li>Not be obese : Very long feedback time</li>
<li>Not have bowel difficulties : Medium feedback time</li>
<li>No soar muscles : Medium feedback time</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>OVERALL GOAL</strong> : Lesser conflicts between body and mind.</p>
<p><em>NOTE</em>: From now on, I might refer to <strong>me as player 1</strong> and <strong>my body as player 2</strong>.</p>
<p>So, this optimization game is biased more towards me feeling good than my body feeling good because the feedback loops associated to the game have easy short-time feedback circuits that favor Player 1. So, it&rsquo;s obvious that the game&rsquo;s results favor me feeling good in the short term rather than both me and my body feeling good in a longer term. So, I needed a way to overcome that.</p>
<p>The optimization game&rsquo;s thus defined. The players in the game are defined. The goals associated with the players are defined. The weight of each action for these players in relation to the goal is defined.</p>
<p>To maximize my overall goal, I thus needed to find a way to make Player 2&rsquo;s goals being equally considered as Player 1&rsquo;s are. I had to change weights on the game in some way that it doesn&rsquo;t discount short-term rewards favoring Player 1 over Player 2&rsquo;s fulfillment.</p>
<p>If I can do this, this changes the situation for Player 2 in the game so both players have an equal say for actions that affect them both.</p>
<p>This is how I increased Player 2&rsquo;s impact in the optimization game. I defined my relationship to my body like a &ldquo;close friend&rdquo;. What that means is that I&rsquo;ll have to maintain basic requisites for being my body&rsquo;s friend. I cannot just abuse it right away, and expect it to maintain a good relationship with me. I cannot be absolutely naive with my best friend, but we can be a bit abusive to each other every now and then. By hitting rough edges and coming together, our friendships get stronger. I treat my body in a similar fashion now.</p>
<p><strong>Let&rsquo;s talk about this with some examples</strong>:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>I want to drink, but I won&rsquo;t go drinking one day after another just to feel good. I will restrain my taste to let my body feel good as well. My body feeling good is me feeling good too but in a longer feedback loop which doesn&rsquo;t feel evident immediately. I will eat unhealthy food randomly over a week but only certain times a week. I don&rsquo;t want to piss my body off. So every time I eat something that&rsquo;s unhealthy, I tell my body to take care of it this time. And my body usually takes care of fewer messes I create. Hence, There will only be a few incidents when I act harshly with my body. Even when I do, there will be a difference in one action after the other, so that we both feel good.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Then, I don&rsquo;t want to exercise. But, my body doesn&rsquo;t want to feel sore because of inactivity. I immediately put exercise as my top priority whenever my body feels even a bit sore. I have to be there for my friend when my friend needs me. On top of that, I&rsquo;ll do exercise sparsely over the week without any schedule since it gives me a dopamine hit immediately afterwards. Previously, I would avoid doing a single physical exercise over months on end whenever I felt busy from my work, but can&rsquo;t avoid like that now. My friend might just fuck me over if I don&rsquo;t maintain my basic friendship. And that puts some obligation to exercise mentally.</p>
<p>I had an interesting insight that came along with this change of weight for Player 2. In trying to change weights of the game for Player 2, the game redefined itself into a 2-player positive sum game. How can this be the case given that our goals conflicted each other ?</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>This happened because I thought eating healthy would be boring. Doing exercise would be boring. But, once you pass the tipping point, you actually start loving the dopamine hit. Now, it feels good to eat healthy. It feels good to not drink on subsequent days. And, my friends rarely push me to break my restraint. Now, it&rsquo;s a positive sum optimization game. My body helps me have fun. I help my body feel good. We both feel good.</p>
<p>I have been spending time thinking why this fooling technique even works at all as well. It sounds so silly, to which, I too agree without a doubt. But, it has worked for me really well over past few years. I have kept my aggressive sinusitis in check, prevented myself from getting fat all over my stomach, and feeling back pain every now and then.</p>
<p>This positive sum game implies that we both try to optimize for each other&rsquo;s best and take care of it to get net positive output for both players.</p>
<p>My reasoning to why this works comes from what modern researchers believe why meditation works.
They note that whenever you meditate, you see your emotions from a 3rd person perspective, without identifying yourself to the same degree, as when you aren&rsquo;t in meditation. We cannot observe facts with clarity when we feel overwhelmed. Thus, by decreasing the intensity of our emotions, meditation helps connect the dots that we were too clouded to see beforehand.
This practice with my body, is in a sense similar, since it detaches me from my body so that I can&rsquo;t do whatever I desire. That decreases the intensity of what I feel in short-term. Because what I desire in the short term is usually not what I want for myself in the long term, I needed to find a way to de-intensify the short term rewards similar to de-intensifying my overwhelming emotions. And the way is to treat my body as a foreign agent ( not me ).</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Brain Facts</title>
            <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2020/07/brain-facts/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2020/07/brain-facts/</guid>
            <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;brain-physiology&#34;&gt;Brain Physiology:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;representation&#34;&gt;Representation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ID: 85b03664-e44a-4ba2-96f8-636cdd41b7c8
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../ox-hugo/_20200706_072643Constudproc.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cerebrum
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Largest part of brain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corpus Callosum
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pathway to connect left and right hemisphere of brain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cerebral Cortex
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Folded structure of cerebrum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frontal Lobe
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part of cerebral cortex just above the eyes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voluntary Movement, Planning, High level Cognitive Skills such as problem
solving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parietal Lobe
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Region just behind the frontal lobe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsible for sensory processing and some visual processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Occipital Lobe
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part of cerebral cortex at the back of the head&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visual processing: Recognizing color and shapes and understanding visual
input&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Temporal Lobe
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part of C.C. at the sides of the head&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsible for visual processing and interpreting auditory information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hippocampus
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curved structure below cerebral cortex&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsible for forming memories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amygdala
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsible for integrating emotions and memories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limbic System
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hippocampus and amygdala together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsible for regulating emotion and motivation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thalamus
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sensory information and relay it to other parts of the brain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forebrain
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All these structures with cerebral cortex&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Midbrain
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beneath the thalamus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coordinate eye movement such as blinking, focusing , triggering reflexes
based on loud noise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fine motor control skills such as writing with pen or playing a musical
instrument&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hindbrain
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glucose regulation, sleep and help control movement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;basal-ganglia&#34;&gt;Basal Ganglia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cerebellum
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tucked underneath occipital lobe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coordinate movement and learn new motor skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pons
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breathing and posture control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Medulla
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nerve pathways from brain to spinal cord&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;brainstem&#34;&gt;Brainstem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thalamocortical loops and EEG&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brain Waves Frequencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="brain-physiology">Brain Physiology:</h2>
<h3 id="representation">Representation</h3>
<pre><code>ID: 85b03664-e44a-4ba2-96f8-636cdd41b7c8
</code></pre>
<figure><img src="/ox-hugo/_20200706_072643Constudproc.png">
</figure>

<h3 id="description">Description</h3>
<ol>
<li>Cerebrum
<ul>
<li>Largest part of brain</li>
<li></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Corpus Callosum
<ul>
<li>Pathway to connect left and right hemisphere of brain</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Cerebral Cortex
<ul>
<li>Folded structure of cerebrum</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Frontal Lobe
<ul>
<li>Part of cerebral cortex just above the eyes</li>
<li>Voluntary Movement, Planning, High level Cognitive Skills such as problem
solving</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Parietal Lobe
<ul>
<li>Region just behind the frontal lobe</li>
<li>Responsible for sensory processing and some visual processing</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Occipital Lobe
<ul>
<li>Part of cerebral cortex at the back of the head</li>
<li>Visual processing: Recognizing color and shapes and understanding visual
input</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Temporal Lobe
<ul>
<li>Part of C.C. at the sides of the head</li>
<li>Responsible for visual processing and interpreting auditory information.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Hippocampus
<ul>
<li>Curved structure below cerebral cortex</li>
<li>Responsible for forming memories</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Amygdala
<ul>
<li>Responsible for integrating emotions and memories</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Limbic System
<ul>
<li>Hippocampus and amygdala together</li>
<li>Responsible for regulating emotion and motivation</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Thalamus
<ul>
<li>Sensory information and relay it to other parts of the brain</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Forebrain
<ul>
<li>All these structures with cerebral cortex</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Midbrain
<ul>
<li>Beneath the thalamus</li>
<li>Coordinate eye movement such as blinking, focusing , triggering reflexes
based on loud noise</li>
<li>Fine motor control skills such as writing with pen or playing a musical
instrument</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Hindbrain
<ul>
<li>Glucose regulation, sleep and help control movement</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<h2 id="basal-ganglia">Basal Ganglia</h2>
</li>
<li>Cerebellum
<ul>
<li>Tucked underneath occipital lobe</li>
<li>Coordinate movement and learn new motor skills</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Pons
<ul>
<li>Breathing and posture control</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Medulla
<ul>
<li>Nerve pathways from brain to spinal cord</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<h2 id="brainstem">Brainstem</h2>
</li>
<li>Thalamocortical loops and EEG</li>
<li>Brain Waves Frequencies</li>
<li></li>
</ol>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Controlling Irrational Thoughts</title>
            <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2020/05/controlling-irrational-thoughts/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2020/05/controlling-irrational-thoughts/</guid>
            <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;solutions&#34;&gt;Solutions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ID: 14c476ff-c39c-47f8-a6f4-cd08e38f4ea1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../ox-hugo/_20200503_013303screenshot.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mindfulness
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowing what you are thinking of and what is happening internally will help
you understand how irrational thoughts surface and develop with time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To help with thought interruptions, keep a timer, rubber band or something
that constantly stays with you and add it to your lifestyle purposefully
for that mental activity interruption.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gratitude
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feel good for all the small yet beautiful things in life. This helps build
positive hormones in the brain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenge irrationalities
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you find yourself nagging without any evidence, challenge yourself to
find evidences for it. Bring logic and rationality to the picture; will
help you realize the futility of a thought drain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meditate
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any way of meditation is helpful for your mind since it&amp;rsquo;s the time you
accept to recognize yourself without subconsciously living a life and
accepting everything that&amp;rsquo;s out there. It will help you get insights, be
more peaceful as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualization
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualization are amazing tools of positive affirmations. If you can
imagine yourself doing and believe it, it will help you attract that
effect. Imagine yourself being confident just like a mantra to repeat at
certain times. This will push yourself to work as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="solutions">Solutions</h2>
<pre><code>ID: 14c476ff-c39c-47f8-a6f4-cd08e38f4ea1
</code></pre>
<figure><img src="/ox-hugo/_20200503_013303screenshot.png">
</figure>

<ol>
<li>Mindfulness
<ul>
<li>Knowing what you are thinking of and what is happening internally will help
you understand how irrational thoughts surface and develop with time.</li>
<li>To help with thought interruptions, keep a timer, rubber band or something
that constantly stays with you and add it to your lifestyle purposefully
for that mental activity interruption.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Gratitude
<ul>
<li>Feel good for all the small yet beautiful things in life. This helps build
positive hormones in the brain.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Challenge irrationalities
<ul>
<li>When you find yourself nagging without any evidence, challenge yourself to
find evidences for it. Bring logic and rationality to the picture; will
help you realize the futility of a thought drain.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Meditate
<ul>
<li>Any way of meditation is helpful for your mind since it&rsquo;s the time you
accept to recognize yourself without subconsciously living a life and
accepting everything that&rsquo;s out there. It will help you get insights, be
more peaceful as well.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Visualization
<ul>
<li>Visualization are amazing tools of positive affirmations. If you can
imagine yourself doing and believe it, it will help you attract that
effect. Imagine yourself being confident just like a mantra to repeat at
certain times. This will push yourself to work as well.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>On Procrastination</title>
            <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2020/05/on-procrastination/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2020/05/on-procrastination/</guid>
            <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;procrastination&#34;&gt;Procrastination&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ID: 2e93fc98-6218-4630-8ff0-1d30c3f6849c
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../ox-hugo/_20200503_010222screenshot.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;problem-1-immensity-of-work&#34;&gt;Problem 1: Immensity of work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You commit to wiping out an entire forest instead of actually starting to
work with a single tree at the moment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even before starting, the mental pressure of the whole big hill over you makes
you more afraid even to start. You try to console yourself that you can do it
in some later point as you don&amp;rsquo;t have the energy to do it now or some reason
to justify not to do it now. The immensity makes it difficult even after days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solution&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="procrastination">Procrastination</h2>
<pre><code>ID: 2e93fc98-6218-4630-8ff0-1d30c3f6849c
</code></pre>
<figure><img src="/ox-hugo/_20200503_010222screenshot.png">
</figure>

<h3 id="problem-1-immensity-of-work">Problem 1: Immensity of work</h3>
<ul>
<li>You commit to wiping out an entire forest instead of actually starting to
work with a single tree at the moment.</li>
</ul>
<!--list-separator-->
<ul>
<li>
<p>What happens?</p>
<ul>
<li>Even before starting, the mental pressure of the whole big hill over you makes
you more afraid even to start. You try to console yourself that you can do it
in some later point as you don&rsquo;t have the energy to do it now or some reason
to justify not to do it now. The immensity makes it difficult even after days.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<!--list-separator-->
<ul>
<li>
<p>Solution</p>
<ul>
<li>Break down a big task into as simple tasks as possible. Like breaking down a
big rock into pebbles. The pebbles should be as simple as they can be such as
setting up your environment and so on.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="problem-2-fear-of-actual-results">Problem 2: Fear of actual results</h3>
<!--list-separator-->
<ul>
<li>
<p>What happens?</p>
<ul>
<li>You want to get gratification by saying: &ldquo;I could have done that amazing task
and I know I would be great at it&rdquo;. You are taking this mental gratification
as a justification for not doing the task at hand. Remember: <strong>&ldquo;You can&rsquo;t edit
a blank page.&rdquo;</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<!--list-separator-->
<ul>
<li>
<p>Solution</p>
<ul>
<li>If you think people will judge you for your results and you think it will make
you feel bad. In fact, people don&rsquo;t even care for most of us. Just because you
have over 1000 friends on Facebook, hundreds of followers on Instagram doesn&rsquo;t
mean they are interested in you. People aren&rsquo;t computers. Even the strongest
of memories fade away: People have to have a grudge on you to remember small
things that you failed even if you failed small. Will you care about them and
not work?</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="problem-3-jumbled-physical-spaces">Problem 3: Jumbled physical spaces</h3>
<ul>
<li>You watch movie, read and sleep on the same bed.</li>
</ul>
<!--list-separator-->
<ul>
<li>
<p>What happens?</p>
<ul>
<li>You have no specific place that you can work on so that sitting on the space
itself helps you commit to work you put off for a long time.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<!--list-separator-->
<ul>
<li>
<p>Solution     :ATTACH:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Your mind&rsquo;s accustomed to working things as automatically as you can.
Creative people, players and even commonly us: We do things unconsciously upon
being in different kinds of environment. Your brain&rsquo;s amazing and does tasks
on it&rsquo;s own as much as it can. But these automatic tasks might not be
favorable at instances. Your body understands to feel drowsy and sleepy when
in bed; So when you feel like being the most productive person on the planet
in your bed, your brain fails you miserably.</p>
<p>So, instead of quarreling with the hundreds of years of evolution, take it to
your advantage. If you separate spaces for your work, sleep and rest; now this
habit of brain helps you to work when you are at physical space representing
work: either it&rsquo;s simple table and chair for you or an entire study room.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<figure><img src="/ox-hugo/_20200503_010547screenshot.png">
    </figure>

</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="problem-4-no-actionable-tasks">Problem 4: No actionable tasks</h3>
<ul>
<li>Even your planned tasks are vague and need more thinking.</li>
</ul>
<!--list-separator-->
<ul>
<li>
<p>What happens?</p>
<ul>
<li>Your tasks need thinking even after you made the plan. Now you drown down the
rabbit hole and the whole loop starts again.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<!--list-separator-->
<ul>
<li>
<p>Solution</p>
<ol>
<li>Two minute rule: Tasks that take two minutes now: just slash them out of your
list. Your list is precious and needs to be as clean as possible. These two
minutes task if ignored for now might take longer later on.</li>
<li>Make tasks actionable: Don&rsquo;t drown into thoughts again : I will do this or
that and all of it. Make simple tasks that you can clearly see yourself
working and start doing it.</li>
<li>Start with something that you find best in that whole rock: a simple crystal
you like. It might not be the first thing to do but to keep you on track and
inspire you: it will be the best place to start.</li>
<li>Plan tasks with actual schedule. Don&rsquo;t even think of situations where you can
compromise later. What if someone calls me for party? This is the worst
thing you can do now. What happens and what to be done if such thing happens
is to be taken care of at that very moment it happens. Don&rsquo;t ever fall into
that trap.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="problem-5-you-are-a-perfectionist">Problem 5: You are a perfectionist</h3>
<ul>
<li>You feel like you have to be the best out there and shouldn&rsquo;t do something
that&rsquo;s not amazing.</li>
</ul>
<!--list-separator-->
<ul>
<li>
<p>What happens?</p>
<ul>
<li>Being a perfectionist but realist at the same time helps but just making
perfect imaginations of anything doesn&rsquo;t help at all. Learn the art of the
start. Be relentless to perfection but for god&rsquo;s sake start with any output
you can have.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<!--list-separator-->
<ul>
<li>
<p>Solution</p>
<ul>
<li>We all want to have the best versions of ourselves to show to others. Noone
wants to be seen weak or incapable. But it&rsquo;s people who start with anything
they have, improvise over time are the ones who accomplish the most. It&rsquo;s okay
to be afraid because it&rsquo;s deep rooted in our brain from earlier times of
evolution. It&rsquo;s a social coping mechanism. People who weren&rsquo;t accepted by
society back in hunting days would die or be killed. We have changed but our
brains are wired the same way. Don&rsquo;t stress over it. Just give time to see
people doing imperfect things. You can start by looking at works of your
favorite YouTubers and movie stars so that you know people you thought are
perfect now were not perfect from the very start. They improvised over time to
be who they are now.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="problem-6-tasks-that-need-internet">Problem 6: Tasks that need Internet</h3>
<ul>
<li>You start working with all your enthusiasm when a certain notification bell
rings on your phone or you start with 10 minutes of Facebook time.</li>
</ul>
<!--list-separator-->
<ul>
<li>
<p>What happens?</p>
<ul>
<li>You get lost searching for things on the internet related to your task and
find at the end of the day that you spent a whole day watching YouTube videos
and browsing Facebook or Reddit or anything you hadn&rsquo;t planned for.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<!--list-separator-->
<ul>
<li>
<p>Solution</p>
<ul>
<li>In today&rsquo;s time, most of us can&rsquo;t work without using internet. While all the
media companies and businesses over internet are there to lure you to spend
more time on their platform, it&rsquo;s a very hard escape out of it. They have been
studying our psychologies and preferences even those which we are not even
conscious of. So, the best thing we can do is be aware. Be present at the
moment. Have a stopwatch tick before you start using Internet or regular
interval checks to at least know when you have plunged into it.
Doing this simple act will change you over time. It&rsquo;s not an overnight thing
but it will create some significant changes.</li>
<li>Use site blockers: the stricter the better. Some cannot even be uninstalled
after you activate them. Make sure to make it as difficult  as possible to
stop them. e.g. Trigger stopping it to deleting all your movies and music from
your hard drive. Just giving some ideas.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="few-last-tips">Few Last Tips</h2>
<ul>
<li>Use Pomodoro technique if you like it. It helps make tasks look simple in
terms of time to commit to tasks.</li>
<li>Use your morning to give a momentum for the day. Just accomplishing simple
tasks as folding your bed or cleaning up your room can give you a feeling of
gratitude and push you to break some more rocks ahead.</li>
<li>Getting Things Done is a nice way to organize your todo lists.</li>
<li>Try to make a weekly review of your todo list so that you know what are
blocking you. You can do shorter reviews such as in 3 days. The faster the
review time: the better the feedback loop. You know your problems better.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Looking Back to School Life</title>
            <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2020/05/looking-back-to-school-life/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2020/05/looking-back-to-school-life/</guid>
            <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-reminiscence&#34;&gt;A Reminiscence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../ox-hugo/school_note.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at this image, I find it funny how we change so much that we are no
longer ourselves. I believed I was this way for as long as I can remember but
alas with time: memories fade, people around you change and you no longer are
the same person that you were before.
This is the first page of my diary I made in my 9th grade.
Looking at the aim I wrote in this diary, it feels so funny and grave misfortune
that I had no idea about the storm of life that was about to burst upon me with
all it&amp;rsquo;s might. I so foolishly believed life was all about being the best in
exams. There&amp;rsquo;s a catch here though: the people I was around, the people who
wanted me to have a bright successful life always came to me and said it: maybe
thousand times or more. My teachers, my parents, my relatives and everyone that
wished well for me.
Either they didn&amp;rsquo;t know that life was so intricate and complex beyond you
passing exams and being best out of it. I believed it to be the holy grail that
would guide my life now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="a-reminiscence">A Reminiscence</h2>
<figure><img src="/ox-hugo/school_note.jpg">
</figure>

<p>Looking at this image, I find it funny how we change so much that we are no
longer ourselves. I believed I was this way for as long as I can remember but
alas with time: memories fade, people around you change and you no longer are
the same person that you were before.
This is the first page of my diary I made in my 9th grade.
Looking at the aim I wrote in this diary, it feels so funny and grave misfortune
that I had no idea about the storm of life that was about to burst upon me with
all it&rsquo;s might. I so foolishly believed life was all about being the best in
exams. There&rsquo;s a catch here though: the people I was around, the people who
wanted me to have a bright successful life always came to me and said it: maybe
thousand times or more. My teachers, my parents, my relatives and everyone that
wished well for me.
Either they didn&rsquo;t know that life was so intricate and complex beyond you
passing exams and being best out of it. I believed it to be the holy grail that
would guide my life now.</p>
<p>Now, Walking along this path, I did what I believed. I became the best version
of who I could be with what I had. Then the wind hit me hard in my face as I
faced the winding road of life. There was no simple aim in anyone&rsquo;s life. I was
with my shield of <strong>being best in exams</strong> and in real life I was as naked as I
could be. Now, the arrows hit me from all sides: arrows being just education and
certificate doesn&rsquo;t make you who you want to be. Life told me: You need to learn
some life skills: hobbies that you can do when you are in pain so that you get
lost in yourself, skills that you can at least earn some money for your
expenses, ability to ask for what you want when you realize the world doesn&rsquo;t give a
damn about you and the fact that you have to go exploring the world rather than
success and happiness coming to you by default.</p>
<p>The quote I wrote there seems amazing to me since myself in that state was all
clear about his life and his path. Yet, that me knew what was going to happen
with my life. For all these years, this quote has been the summary of my life. I
feared ever trying to give 100% to anything. I always left when I felt it was
finally up to the top. I felt an urge to back down when I saw the peak. It was
never that I didn&rsquo;t have the knowledge or the skills I needed, it was just I was
afraid of falling on the way to the mountaintop.
All this has come to me after 8 years. I wished I could write this letter to
that me 8 years back.Would it have mattered? Would I have listened to myself? That&rsquo;s a
question that will forever remain.</p>
<p>I have gone through a horrible path to get out of this belief. I hope no child
is taught that exams are the way to better life: life is much more than that. I
hope noone has to go this long to realize their beliefs were a lie.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>गजल</title>
            <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2020/05/%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%9C%E0%A4%B2/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2020/05/%E0%A4%97%E0%A4%9C%E0%A4%B2/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;तिम्रो बोली गुलाबको फूल मनमा भने काँडा रैछ
झुटो मेरो वचन होइन पापी तिम्रो आँखा रैछ ।&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;माया प्रेमको अन्धकारमा हराएको मेरो दृष्टि
नयन हेर्दा निर्दोष तिमी मनमा भने ढुसी रैछ ।&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;सुन्दरताको मोहजालमा तड्पाएर मेरो शरीर
अङ्ग भङ्ग पारी शरीर बेच्ने तिम्रो चाहा रैछ ।&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;जीवनको नाटककी पारङ्गत कलाकार तिमी
मायाको अमृतमा लोभ्याएर विष मिसाई पीलाउनु रैछ ।&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;तिम्रो केशको छायाँमा नै जीवन जिउँछु भन्ने मलाई
त्यै केशको फन्दा बनाई प्याक्क पारी मार्नु रैछ ।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>तिम्रो बोली गुलाबको फूल मनमा भने काँडा रैछ
झुटो मेरो वचन होइन पापी तिम्रो आँखा रैछ ।</p>
<p>माया प्रेमको अन्धकारमा हराएको मेरो दृष्टि
नयन हेर्दा निर्दोष तिमी मनमा भने ढुसी रैछ ।</p>
<p>सुन्दरताको मोहजालमा तड्पाएर मेरो शरीर
अङ्ग भङ्ग पारी शरीर बेच्ने तिम्रो चाहा रैछ ।</p>
<p>जीवनको नाटककी पारङ्गत कलाकार तिमी
मायाको अमृतमा लोभ्याएर विष मिसाई पीलाउनु रैछ ।</p>
<p>तिम्रो केशको छायाँमा नै जीवन जिउँछु भन्ने मलाई
त्यै केशको फन्दा बनाई प्याक्क पारी मार्नु रैछ ।</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Tentacles of Thoughts</title>
            <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2020/04/tentacles-of-thoughts/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 16:26:42 +0545</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2020/04/tentacles-of-thoughts/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Inside the dark vents of my body,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lies the vines: of growing darkness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying to find it&amp;rsquo;s way to my brain,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It sweeps, explodes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It grunges from the inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There used to be garden inside,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thoughts laid peace within me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fights were always physical then,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peace was a habit,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And thoughts resembled curiosity then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The darkness grew out of the worldly ways,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stories of success,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stories of failures,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Inside the dark vents of my body,</p>
<p>Lies the vines: of growing darkness.</p>
<p>Trying to find it&rsquo;s way to my brain,</p>
<p>It sweeps, explodes</p>
<p>It grunges from the inside.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>There used to be garden inside,</p>
<p>Thoughts laid peace within me.</p>
<p>Fights were always physical then,</p>
<p>Peace was a habit,</p>
<p>And thoughts resembled curiosity then.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The darkness grew out of the worldly ways,</p>
<p>The stories of success,</p>
<p>The stories of failures,</p>
<p>The horrors of living,</p>
<p>The ephemeral life,</p>
<p>And the drive to thrive.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Now,</p>
<p>With a gasp it starts,</p>
<p>Slowly it finds it&rsquo;s way</p>
<p>Creepy they are,</p>
<p>Creeping through me like swinging vines,</p>
<p>Stranded and clogged.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Walls of mind and tentacles of thoughts,</p>
<p>The war of the microcosm,</p>
<p>The dance of the devil form.</p>
<p>My bones are still the same,</p>
<p>My muscles undeformed,</p>
<p>But it feels like</p>
<p>The quarks inside them want some deadly transform.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Cold it is,</p>
<p>To fight with ownself.</p>
<p>Hard it is,</p>
<p>To break the chains of thoughts.</p>
<p>Pain it is,</p>
<p>To not understand anyone but ownself.</p>
<p>Peace it is,</p>
<p>To lay inside the box in peace</p>
<p>With tentacles of thoughts buried to the ground.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Peak</title>
            <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2020/04/peak/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 16:22:45 +0545</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2020/04/peak/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peak&lt;/strong&gt; they saw,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thought they made,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the day when their steps would be on the mountain peak,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clear seem&amp;rsquo;d they, Of the goal they desperately seek.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guided&lt;/strong&gt; by the river trail,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dreams flew high against the flow,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mountains of hope: deep and strong first,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now saw the wind of fear that slowly blow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The path&lt;/strong&gt; feels rough now,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The silent howls of people&amp;rsquo;s voice he heard,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of those who got lost on that way,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Peak</strong> they saw,</p>
<p>Thought they made,</p>
<p>Of the day when their steps would be on the mountain peak,</p>
<p>Clear seem&rsquo;d they, Of the goal they desperately seek.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Guided</strong> by the river trail,</p>
<p>Dreams flew high against the flow,</p>
<p>The mountains of hope: deep and strong first,</p>
<p>Now saw the wind of fear that slowly blow.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The path</strong> feels rough now,</p>
<p>The silent howls of people&rsquo;s voice he heard,</p>
<p>Of those who got lost on that way,</p>
<p>And of those who sought to walk away.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>His heart</strong> gets cold,</p>
<p>The body gets blue,</p>
<p>Creeping from the inside out,</p>
<p>Growls the wolf wishing to devour his vow.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My First Vipassana Experience</title>
            <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2017/10/my-first-vipassana-experience/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2017/10/my-first-vipassana-experience/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The journey of it starts with a recommendation from two of my friends. I, being desperate to experience something spiritual and majestic, decided to take on a 10 day Vipasana course.
Being an Engineering student from tech related field, it&amp;rsquo;s quiet essential for you to cope through the old dying syllabus and find yourself some life through the Internet. The rapid outbursts in Physics and Technology like the Neural Networks,researches on the quantum field with startling papers like &amp;ldquo;Universe shouldn&amp;rsquo;t exist&amp;rdquo; made my mind wander a lot beyond my control.
It was as if knowledge was on a different level trying to exploit the unconscious parts of the universal intellect as well as mine. Having read a lot but pretty much experienced nothing in particular as per I read, it was one of the reasons to give a fair try. But mostly I wanted a piece of my mind to recognize my deep interests among the disruptive tech bubbles in a 10 days self-exploration. Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to move.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The journey of it starts with a recommendation from two of my friends. I, being desperate to experience something spiritual and majestic, decided to take on a 10 day Vipasana course.
Being an Engineering student from tech related field, it&rsquo;s quiet essential for you to cope through the old dying syllabus and find yourself some life through the Internet. The rapid outbursts in Physics and Technology like the Neural Networks,researches on the quantum field with startling papers like &ldquo;Universe shouldn&rsquo;t exist&rdquo; made my mind wander a lot beyond my control.
It was as if knowledge was on a different level trying to exploit the unconscious parts of the universal intellect as well as mine. Having read a lot but pretty much experienced nothing in particular as per I read, it was one of the reasons to give a fair try. But mostly I wanted a piece of my mind to recognize my deep interests among the disruptive tech bubbles in a 10 days self-exploration. Now it&rsquo;s time to move.</p>
<p>The South East Asia is quiet known for it&rsquo;s spiritual gifts to the West. But there is a run between these two sides: running towards one another.
But with the hike of knowledge at a tremendous pace, people have been quiet keen towards ancient wisdom and spirituality more than ever at this point of time. I told my parents about it and they were shocked to see their son go for a meditation. The fear was quiet clear: If I discard the ways of society and talk of high philosophies like a monk leaving the normal life back away.
We are quiet amazing people,you see. We always are proud of the fact that Buddha was born in our country but are afraid to even take a step towards learning his teachings. You, me and most of us are same. It&rsquo;s just the ways we are afraid to go against the ways our minds are shaped for the past few centuries. We are evolving, breaking chains wherever we can but a very tardy pace.
I somehow managed to convince them to go for it and now it officially starts.</p>
<p>This is my experience on a substantial level because the kind of internal experience is kinda difficult to explain in a few words.</p>
<p>It was at Dhamma Pokhara I was going to meditate. Started from Begnas bus station, I had to reach the center by 1 and found out buses move in about every 30 minutes. So, I bought myself a cold drink bottle and decided to move. Hey bro, don&rsquo;t talk about even a bottle of coke man. It&rsquo;s boring. Yeah I know but lets see whats up next. My mind is fickle and I contemplate a lot. On a scale out of 10, might be 11 as well. I asked a local for time to reach center from the station who said it was about 15 to 20 minutes. It was about 12:20 when I started. I walked like till 12:45 and asked a person on the way and again like 10 to 15 minutes. It happens a lot of time, maybe even to you too.I got a bus fortunately. On the way, I felt like If I take bottle of coke to meditation, they would feel like if I was not really up for meditation, so I threw it away. The reason I got myself then makes me laugh at myself now. They gave instruction for direction but I got confused on the words used to explain it. I asked a man nearby where Vipasana was and he didn&rsquo;t know the word.I wandered around and reached there by 12:55.</p>
<p>I was shocked by the view. I mean the people: almost everyone was like with these huge baggages and I had like a couple of clothes for 10 days and a brush only to be honest.Actually, I was thinking to get soap and a paste on the way but rush took everything out. They had like meditational tools and I was like Oh fuck, How do I even fit here? Then it started. I was even worrying for the interview they wrote on the email. What if I they send me home back? Actually there was no interview at all. I kept myself busy with these disturbing thoughts.
Now you get a pretty clear idea of this creepy guy to go for a meditation. I was in a group of 17 males and there were just two other Nepalese people, quiet old and couldn&rsquo;t understand English. The meditation was to start from tomorrow officially, so we were allowed to talk that day till the orientation at 5 pm.</p>
<p>Now, the talk started. I started to talk with an Indian guy. We were like in a group of three and this Nepalese uncle said he already had this experience. So we started listening to him. I was pretty much the translator for these guys. The uncle talked in Nepali and I would tell the Indian guy in English and vice versa. So, the philosophies were quiet high from the uncle&rsquo;s experience as he spoke. He spoke pretty much like a big guru does. I was constantly feeling a lot of exaggeration. When I got to know the Indian guy from the North East part of India, He was so cool and amazing. We were talking of the spiritual things around the world where I told him about my experience of meditation high on weed and got to know about LSD, DMT and bigger mind game changers. He told me DMT trip was like a time travel trip. I thought it was exaggeration too but as I got to know him more maybe there&rsquo;s a chance of being it partially true. He was up around with knowledge of the world from IBM&rsquo;s Watson to Neural networks although by profession, He is a baker. Baker, listening this word you might get a feeling and a poor complaint image. I pretty much would have done so if I hadn&rsquo;t learned him earlier.
But he was pretty much what I wanted in my life till that time. A search for spirituality, lot of traveling and a cool life. It was pretty much the way I wished myself to morph to.</p>
<p>Talking was amazing and the view of the common junction of male and female areas (There was a complete segregation of male and female residences, kitchen and all except the meditation hall for 10 days) Yeah, pretty hard to not take a look if you find someone attractive. I talked to other few. So, it was said in email about 17 males. I haven&rsquo;t talked to them properly so I put a nickname over everyone to contemplate about these people for 10 days.</p>
<p>Let me introduce you to them:
Me, The Amazing Indian Guy, The Nepalese uncle, The Nepalese Grandfather, The Shaman Guy, The Ninja guy, The Silent Roomie, ( The last three were my roommates), The Yoga guy, The Beard Guy, The Brad Pitt Guy, The Sadistic Guy,
The Indian tech Guy, The Indian Blank Guy, The Brown Mustache Guy, The Harry Potter Guy, The FBI guy, The Yogi volunteer
I don&rsquo;t know why I put the word &ldquo;Guy&rdquo; behind everyone. So lets leave it.
Now let me explain why I named them so.
You pretty much understand a few, rest I&rsquo;ll explain. On the first day, The Shaman Guy was talking about something I didn&rsquo;t understand and in midst I hear this word Shaman and looked fancy cuz I didn&rsquo;t know what it meant.
The Ninja Guy: He was cutting bamboo and rest behind our dorms and making a stick to play with his fingers like a Ninja. I thought he was not serious in meditation at all from the very first moment.
The FBI guy: I contemplated for 10 days to uncover the secret behind the numbers pasted in his bottle. He looked gloomy at the beginning. Maybe, he is hiding right here.
The numbers were pasted by his brother and it was some kind of Japanese technique of wishing good to someone.
Oh my poor thoughts&hellip; They were into everything on a damn uncomfortable level.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t know anyone except two on this first day and now we are going to live together for 10 days without even talking with expressions.</p>
<p>Lets start the 10 days journey. You are experiencing a vivid journey of 10 days of meditation, so better take a long breath before we start.
I have one task for you. Wherever you feel like I am exaggerating something, increase the count. Let&rsquo;s see how much I can exaggerate this experience.</p>
<p>Day 1:
The time table is so strict to get up soon and start meditating all day. This is first day contemplating how shit I was to forget the soap and toothpaste. I was into it. I ate, I slept easy though. It was like easy meditation for the first day.
The meals I thought I would not survive out of it. There was no dinner and still need to wake up so early. I am quiet an early bird and I thought it was like back home:hungry when I woke up but it went quiet the opposite. The diet was actually
enough since we had no mechanical work except walk a few steps on the walking trail inside the center. But one thing was missing. We got a very good view of mountains and lake from there and it was usurped from us. Ugh&hellip; painful.
This was the best scene and they keep it restricted. It was a perfect place to meditate like the sagas of sages describes. It was the night I suffocated due to my blanket and felt horrible. I couldn&rsquo;t breathe for about a minute.
However, I felt asleep soon.</p>
<p>Day 2:
The nature was pretty amazing and from the dining seat, it was such a beautiful scenario. Today, a thorn was taken out. There came a slip in dining with a notice that if somebody wanted the supplies like soaps, toothpaste etc.
They could ask now and pay on the tenth day. A long sigh&hellip; A big relief for me. In the mornings and evenings, almost everyone was like standing on the trail looking at the last light when the day is finally going to be over.
Machhapuchre from the side and Annapurna: they were standing so peaceful. They were like soft from the inside and determined from the inside,stronger than everything. I was also worried if I get to take a good bath because the meal break
didn&rsquo;t use to be long. What if all went for the bathroom at the same time? I was worried about these little things that actually didn&rsquo;t make any difference in my life. This was the time I got to see a butterfly that I fell in love with.
It was matte black from inside and pretty oraange and yellow from outside. It had like two tails and it&rsquo;s movements were like those of a beautiful dancer on one of big stages. I tried hard to get it into my hand and see closely.
After waiting patiently for 30 minutes or so I got it. It was like achieving something great.</p>
<p>Day 3:
The meditational techniques were changing and I was trying to get my questions answered rather than the meditation itself. I would do for few moments the exercise they tell me to do then my mind would wander so fast. I was letting my mind
go wherever it wants because I thought how much thoughts could I possibly have when there&rsquo;s nothing happening new and you would pretty much contemplate everything. I had believed that in 4 or 5 days I would think so much that my over thinking thoughts would come to an end and I was just doing it. One funny thing I tried: I saw one of the guys walking bare footed. Just to look like a serious meditator, I also took off my slippers and walked around like I had attained some heavenly
Nirvana or something. Counting the end of 10 days was like: The 9th and 10th, a feeling that just one day will make everything easy. So 5 days more I was soothing myself.</p>
<p>Day 4:
This day, I looked at myself and thought I need to cut my beard off. If I cut it now, my face won&rsquo;t look like one of a child. I had tried partly on my previous year&rsquo;s vacation, so I knew it well. So, I thought to myself these people don&rsquo;t know me and also don&rsquo;t talk to me, so I will shave my beard this day. But as I said I had no razor or anything. So, I wrote for a razor on that day and waited for it to come. In the meantime, I&rsquo;d think like what would I do if they give me a Rs 5 blade and I cut my neck off. It took about 4 hours of that day&rsquo;s contemplation from time to time. It came again and again those pictures like I was cutting my throat and all. It was quiet disturbing to observe my reality from this point of time now. We were taught Vipasana this day and three hours of serious meditation as well. A lot of back pain, a lot and lot I tell you.</p>
<p>Day 5:
Now the meditation seems to be a bit deeper. Everyone seems to be more focused than they were before trying harder into it. The fear of razor was still haunting me in between. If I don&rsquo;t get a razor today I thought by the time I will be out, I will be like a kid, I feared.
Sometimes, I would get into meditation procedure quickly and be focused but sometimes it didn&rsquo;t focus at all. It was really true: I was a prisoner of my own mind. It became a lot clearer by this day.
The sedimentation and decantation of my thoughts was taking no seriousness, the thoughts do persist even now and I was amazed by the quantity. It was an endless river and I thought was never coming to an end.
Also, the body ached a lot. Everyone is doing some stretching or yoga. I am trying to copy some of them and it was fun. I think it&rsquo;s the day I saw the full moon so beautiful. There were webs all over trees and grass. The moon shining through
the thin fabric of spider&rsquo;s web, just imagine it yourself.</p>
<p>Day 6:
This day, I get a razor. Wow.. still 4 days left. Let&rsquo;s do it. They got me a good one. Fortunately,The memo of shave was short: I mean the cuts. :D Now I am a bit serious. I really felt like walking not just to be so but to feel the ground beneath me.
To feel everything that happens inside and outside me. I was looking at the mountains and they were getting more white each day, more beautiful each day. One more was a single boat in my entire view of lake. Everyone is quiet and into nature, more peaceful.</p>
<p>Day 7:
This was probably the best day I could remember. I got up at like 2. I didnt have a watch. Who keeps one on this age of cellphones, I thought. I realized I liked to have a watch now although I will have my phone when I am out.
I had a lucid dream that answered a few part of my questions I was searching for. Then, I went to meditate and focused for an hour or so. I suddenly get an amazing thought in between and was so much happy. I got out and walked around two rounds of the trail
without slippers. The cold was soothing my over-excitement of happiness and I knew I needed to be calm now as well. Now I was meditating well and suddenly I had a boner on the middle of meditation and changed my position to a comfortable one
:one like a super enjoying type. The volunteer came up to me to change the position while I think everyone was closing their eyes. I was red and shy. Oh man&hellip; I got it over in a hour. If I was out and experienced such a situation, I&rsquo;d feel like
shame for a maybe a week.</p>
<p>Day 8:
The previous day I was so much into meditation and enjoying myself as well. But starting this day was a bit difficult. I was asking myself questions and searching for answers rather than trying the meditational procedure. And in the daytime,
I glanced a volleyball match on the other side of the lake. I was looking from the spaces in between the branches of trees to get a view of what&rsquo;s on the other side. The bset part was to move here and there and create partial views to finally
understand the complete view of the other side. The moment &ldquo;The Ninja Guy&rdquo; left, one space in room made another one in my heart. I can leave as well since I have got what I was looking for. It was like some kind of loneliness and more of impatience.</p>
<p>&amp;nbsp;</p>
<p>Day 9:
This day was more like pain because three had left already and I couldn&rsquo;t concerntrate on myself. Now, The Yoga guy left. I felt he was serious towards this meditation but left. I felt kind of a despir within me. The clock was moving like a snail and my thoughts were trying to eat me back again. I was more peaceful than before but not as calm as I thought I had become.
My stomach still blurped when I thought of something I feared. The mountains and lake were quiet the motivation. Their calmness was the only helping key and later on I was meditating a bit better. One beautiful moment was my play with a butterfly with my long shadow.
I was kinda like an innocent and peaceful child. ;) The rest of the day went on with nothing special.</p>
<p>Day 10:
This day was out of my count for first 7 days. But, On the eighth, it came to be a big clock ticking like months to pass hours for last two days. But after the morning meditation, breakfast was served. That breakfast: the smell, the foods, the number of dishes on your seat Just Wow.
Everyone&rsquo;s face was sparkling so bright and smiling with themselves. I kinda glanced at someone and shared a smile because it was a big happiness considering my mind status for last two days. There were nine dishes for breakfast.
My tummy had no place for fruits. This was oh&hellip; imagine the most beautiful word you can get and fill the blanks.
It was on the 10th when I experienced something like heavenly with a particle like thing on my backbone. It was moving up and down and moves up to head and felt like a tree was growing in my brain. I was laughing with myself.
As a kid, when someone plays you to make you laugh and ask to stop, it was somehow similar. This was just a unexpected sensation and nothing more but beautiful.
Now it was the talking time at 10. As my friend had told he was like silent for a month after return but I was jolly, too eager to get enlightened by their experiences.
When we started talking, there was no stop to it. The view was mesmerizing all around, the expressions of happiness and it was certainly heavenly. Now I get to know them on a deeper level. We talked all along although we had meditation sessions in between.
So much talking&hellip; whoo. The Shaman guy was the boss of a textile industry and his story was amazing. He had meditational blocks made by Nike. Nike WTF? Yeah Nike even made these. I saw a lot of equipments used for making meditations easy, I didnt even know these existed.
Earning money and owning something was quiet different from what I thought. He wanted to get out off his own company at that time and this whole trip without asking for a leave was a sign for them to understand it, he said.
There was a guy who left an IT company he started and walked around without a thought of what he might be at his country back. During the meditation days, I felt as if he had big trouble. On this day, I came to knew all about his company but he seemed less troubled now.
I talked a lot and lot, might-be most talked to him after the Indian one. It not only was peace for him to share but for me as well. Somethings resonated to my thoughts and taught me something precious.
Their professions Biomedical Engineers, System Design at Cisco, Entrepreneurs and all. The difference between us and them is that they work a lot when they need to. I think I was the youngest of the group, so I experienced so much of life from around the world in those 10 days.
Maybe, it will take me even 40 years to travel 4 or 5 countries as per the current scenario. So, it was quiet mesmerizing.</p>
<p>The journey ended in the morning of 11th day 7 am.</p>
<p>The experience I shared is mostly the outwards experience. I cannot share in words what I truly felt from the inside. As you can Google for things like DMT trips and all, it was kind of one. I always rushed away from my thoughts, it was
the first time I just observed them. Everyone speaks of not being able to control themselves but most of us don&rsquo;t even want to give a try. A try to tame your wild bull, a try to think things from some different perspective than you
usually live in and mostly to experience something amazing everyone felt who have been to Vipasana. I have found quiet unlikely that people express this ten days meditation as a waste of time because those who experienced it are quiet
eager to speak and motivate others to go to it. It means it&rsquo;s something different. Quiet out from religious dogmas, it is quiet more like a dissection of yourself by yourself. So, in a belief that I could ask more of you to experience
the thing I experienced, to be able to hear more stories and motivate each others to continue this practise. We have a facility even free of cost which says by itself that Volunteering is the greatest donation rather than money and expects
your happiness in return for the 10 days experience, why not give it a try.
The outwards experience and learning as mine might differ from place you choose to go to meditate but the internal feelings of happiness will pretty much be same. If you like it, share it. Share your experiences as well. I will be more than happy to hear of your wonderful feelings.
Ask others to join you when you complete one. Let&rsquo;s try what we have at our own doorsteps by taking 10 days out our hectic life not for someone else but for own self. If you cannot find 10 days, go for shorter ones or simply go and have a seat in one of those. You are most likely to feel a different vibration because of the place they have set up just by volunteering. If you think I have exaggerated, I haven&rsquo;t. You can give a fair try to it in many Vipasana centers across the country. I want to thank Vipasana center, my friends during the meditation, management and everyone heartfully for providing me this amazing experience to share with you all. Thank you all for going through this long writing patiently as well.</p>
<p>May all be happy and peaceful. Bhawatu Saba Mangala.:)</p>
<h2 id="some-memories">Some Memories</h2>
<figure><img src="/ox-hugo/_20230904_110027screenshot.png"
    alt="Figure 1: Cristoph&rsquo;s stone made counting device for 10 days: 10 lines"><figcaption>
      <p><span class="figure-number">Figure 1: </span>Cristoph&rsquo;s stone made counting device for 10 days: 10 lines</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure><img src="/ox-hugo/_20230904_110152screenshot.png"
    alt="Figure 2: View I lived with for 10 days"><figcaption>
      <p><span class="figure-number">Figure 2: </span>View I lived with for 10 days</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure><img src="/ox-hugo/_20230904_110307screenshot.png"
    alt="Figure 3: Group Photo 11th day"><figcaption>
      <p><span class="figure-number">Figure 3: </span>Group Photo 11th day</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure><img src="/ox-hugo/_20230904_110358screenshot.png"
    alt="Figure 4: Cloudy view of the Mountains"><figcaption>
      <p><span class="figure-number">Figure 4: </span>Cloudy view of the Mountains</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure><img src="/ox-hugo/_20230904_110459screenshot.png"
    alt="Figure 5: A Lonely Boat Cr: Dominique"><figcaption>
      <p><span class="figure-number">Figure 5: </span>A Lonely Boat Cr: Dominique</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>सत्य</title>
            <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2015/05/%E0%A4%B8%E0%A4%A4%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%AF/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2015/05/%E0%A4%B8%E0%A4%A4%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%AF/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;आकाङ्क्षाका पानाहरुमा&lt;br&gt;
समेटिएको यो जीवनमा&lt;br&gt;
च्यातिएका ती पानाहरु&lt;br&gt;
स्वयमहित्को तान्डवसँगै&lt;br&gt;
कुल्चिएका भावनाहरु ।&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;तिनै जलेका पानाहरु&lt;br&gt;
धुँवा बनी उडेको छ&lt;br&gt;
संसार जस्तो भएपनि&lt;br&gt;
अदृश्यतामा रमेकोछ ।&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;हिमालका ती कोप्चारामा&lt;br&gt;
हिउँसँगै जमेकोछ ।।&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;सुरको धुनमा बज्दा यसलाई&lt;br&gt;
शब्दकोशमा खोजेपछि&lt;br&gt;
आफुलाई नचाहरि&lt;br&gt;
धर्मग्रन्थ रटेपछि&lt;br&gt;
न्यायका ती किताबले नै&lt;br&gt;
सत्यतालाई ढाकेपछि ।&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;सत्य आज मरिसक्यो&lt;br&gt;
जीवनलाई छाडेपछि&lt;br&gt;
मृत्यु सत्य बनिसक्यो&lt;br&gt;
सत्य खोज्न थालेपछि ।।&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;गढिमाईको मन्दीरमा&lt;br&gt;
मृत्यु नै त सत्य बन्यो&lt;br&gt;
न्याय बन्यो धर्म बन्यो&lt;br&gt;
सत्य सँधै एक्लो बन्यो ।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>आकाङ्क्षाका पानाहरुमा<br>
समेटिएको यो जीवनमा<br>
च्यातिएका ती पानाहरु<br>
स्वयमहित्को तान्डवसँगै<br>
कुल्चिएका भावनाहरु ।</p>
<p>तिनै जलेका पानाहरु<br>
धुँवा बनी उडेको छ<br>
संसार जस्तो भएपनि<br>
अदृश्यतामा रमेकोछ ।</p>
<p>हिमालका ती कोप्चारामा<br>
हिउँसँगै जमेकोछ ।।</p>
<p> </p>
<p>सुरको धुनमा बज्दा यसलाई<br>
शब्दकोशमा खोजेपछि<br>
आफुलाई नचाहरि<br>
धर्मग्रन्थ रटेपछि<br>
न्यायका ती किताबले नै<br>
सत्यतालाई ढाकेपछि ।</p>
<p>सत्य आज मरिसक्यो<br>
जीवनलाई छाडेपछि<br>
मृत्यु सत्य बनिसक्यो<br>
सत्य खोज्न थालेपछि ।।</p>
<p> </p>
<p>गढिमाईको मन्दीरमा<br>
मृत्यु नै त सत्य बन्यो<br>
न्याय बन्यो धर्म बन्यो<br>
सत्य सँधै एक्लो बन्यो ।</p>
<p>कतै मुस्कान लहरसँगै<br>
कतै रगत खोलो बग्यो<br>
आलो रगत चरुसँगै<br>
सत्य यज्ञ भष्म बन्यो ।</p>
<p>त्यै भष्मको कालो टीका<br>
धर्मको त प्रतिक बन्यो<br>
सत्य अब जलिसक्यो<br>
यो माटोलाई त्यागिसक्यो<br>
विनाशतिर लम्काएर<br>
संसारदेखि भागिसक्यो ।।</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
