<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Alok&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Alok&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 16:26:42 +0545</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://dragarok.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Tentacles of Thoughts</title>
            <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2020/04/tentacles-of-thoughts/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 16:26:42 +0545</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/2020/04/tentacles-of-thoughts/</guid>
            <description>Inside the dark vents of my body,
Lies the vines: of growing darkness.
Trying to find it&amp;rsquo;s way to my brain,
It sweeps, explodes
It grunges from the inside.
There used to be garden inside,
Thoughts laid peace within me.
Fights were always physical then,
Peace was a habit,
And thoughts resembled curiosity then.
The darkness grew out of the worldly ways,
The stories of success,
The stories of failures,</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Inside the dark vents of my body,</p>
<p>Lies the vines: of growing darkness.</p>
<p>Trying to find it&rsquo;s way to my brain,</p>
<p>It sweeps, explodes</p>
<p>It grunges from the inside.</p>
<p>There used to be garden inside,</p>
<p>Thoughts laid peace within me.</p>
<p>Fights were always physical then,</p>
<p>Peace was a habit,</p>
<p>And thoughts resembled curiosity then.</p>
<p>The darkness grew out of the worldly ways,</p>
<p>The stories of success,</p>
<p>The stories of failures,</p>
<p>The horrors of living,</p>
<p>The ephemeral life,</p>
<p>And the drive to thrive.</p>
<p>Now,</p>
<p>With a gasp it starts,</p>
<p>Slowly it finds it&rsquo;s way</p>
<p>Creepy they are,</p>
<p>Creeping through me like swinging vines,</p>
<p>Stranded and clogged.</p>
<p>Walls of mind and tentacles of thoughts,</p>
<p>The war of the microcosm,</p>
<p>The dance of the devil form.</p>
<p>My bones are still the same,</p>
<p>My muscles undeformed,</p>
<p>But it feels like</p>
<p>The quarks inside them want some deadly transform.</p>
<p>Cold it is,</p>
<p>To fight with ownself.</p>
<p>Hard it is,</p>
<p>To break the chains of thoughts.</p>
<p>Pain it is,</p>
<p>To not understand anyone but ownself.</p>
<p>Peace it is,</p>
<p>To lay inside the box in peace</p>
<p>With tentacles of thoughts buried to the ground.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My First Vipassana Experience</title>
            <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/1/01/my-first-vipassana-experience/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/1/01/my-first-vipassana-experience/</guid>
            <description>The journey of it starts with a recommendation from two of my friends. I, being desperate to experience something spiritual and majestic, decided to take on a 10 day Vipasana course. Being an Engineering student from tech related field, it&amp;rsquo;s quiet essential for you to cope through the old dying syllabus and find yourself some life through the Internet. The rapid outbursts in Physics and Technology like the Neural Networks,researches on the quantum field with startling papers like &amp;ldquo;Universe shouldn&amp;rsquo;t exist&amp;rdquo; made my mind wander a lot beyond my control.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The journey of it starts with a recommendation from two of my friends. I, being desperate to experience something spiritual and majestic, decided to take on a 10 day Vipasana course.
Being an Engineering student from tech related field, it&rsquo;s quiet essential for you to cope through the old dying syllabus and find yourself some life through the Internet. The rapid outbursts in Physics and Technology like the Neural Networks,researches on the quantum field with startling papers like &ldquo;Universe shouldn&rsquo;t exist&rdquo; made my mind wander a lot beyond my control.
It was as if knowledge was on a different level trying to exploit the unconscious parts of the universal intellect as well as mine. Having read a lot but pretty much experienced nothing in particular as per I read, it was one of the reasons to give a fair try. But mostly I wanted a piece of my mind to recognize my deep interests among the disruptive tech bubbles in a 10 days self-exploration. Now it&rsquo;s time to move.</p>
<p>The South East Asia is quiet known for it&rsquo;s spiritual gifts to the West. But there is a run between these two sides: running towards one another.
But with the hike of knowledge at a tremendous pace, people have been quiet keen towards ancient wisdom and spirituality more than ever at this point of time. I told my parents about it and they were shocked to see their son go for a meditation. The fear was quiet clear: If I discard the ways of society and talk of high philosophies like a monk leaving the normal life back away.
We are quiet amazing people,you see. We always are proud of the fact that Buddha was born in our country but are afraid to even take a step towards learning his teachings. You, me and most of us are same. It&rsquo;s just the ways we are afraid to go against the ways our minds are shaped for the past few centuries. We are evolving, breaking chains wherever we can but a very tardy pace.
I somehow managed to convince them to go for it and now it officially starts.</p>
<p>This is my experience on a substantial level because the kind of internal experience is kinda difficult to explain in a few words.</p>
<p>It was at Dhamma Pokhara I was going to meditate. Started from Begnas bus station, I had to reach the center by 1 and found out buses move in about every 30 minutes. So, I bought myself a cold drink bottle and decided to move. Hey bro, don&rsquo;t talk about even a bottle of coke man. It&rsquo;s boring. Yeah I know but lets see whats up next. My mind is fickle and I contemplate a lot. On a scale out of 10, might be 11 as well. I asked a local for time to reach center from the station who said it was about 15 to 20 minutes. It was about 12:20 when I started. I walked like till 12:45 and asked a person on the way and again like 10 to 15 minutes. It happens a lot of time, maybe even to you too.I got a bus fortunately. On the way, I felt like If I take bottle of coke to meditation, they would feel like if I was not really up for meditation, so I threw it away. The reason I got myself then makes me laugh at myself now. They gave instruction for direction but I got confused on the words used to explain it. I asked a man nearby where Vipasana was and he didn&rsquo;t know the word.I wandered around and reached there by 12:55.</p>
<p>I was shocked by the view. I mean the people: almost everyone was like with these huge baggages and I had like a couple of clothes for 10 days and a brush only to be honest.Actually, I was thinking to get soap and a paste on the way but rush took everything out. They had like meditational tools and I was like Oh fuck, How do I even fit here? Then it started. I was even worrying for the interview they wrote on the email. What if I they send me home back? Actually there was no interview at all. I kept myself busy with these disturbing thoughts.
Now you get a pretty clear idea of this creepy guy to go for a meditation. I was in a group of 17 males and there were just two other Nepalese people, quiet old and couldn&rsquo;t understand English. The meditation was to start from tomorrow officially, so we were allowed to talk that day till the orientation at 5 pm.</p>
<p>Now, the talk started. I started to talk with an Indian guy. We were like in a group of three and this Nepalese uncle said he already had this experience. So we started listening to him. I was pretty much the translator for these guys. The uncle talked in Nepali and I would tell the Indian guy in English and vice versa. So, the philosophies were quiet high from the uncle&rsquo;s experience as he spoke. He spoke pretty much like a big guru does. I was constantly feeling a lot of exaggeration. When I got to know the Indian guy from the North East part of India, He was so cool and amazing. We were talking of the spiritual things around the world where I told him about my experience of meditation high on weed and got to know about LSD, DMT and bigger mind game changers. He told me DMT trip was like a time travel trip. I thought it was exaggeration too but as I got to know him more maybe there&rsquo;s a chance of being it partially true. He was up around with knowledge of the world from IBM&rsquo;s Watson to Neural networks although by profession, He is a baker. Baker, listening this word you might get a feeling and a poor complaint image. I pretty much would have done so if I hadn&rsquo;t learned him earlier.
But he was pretty much what I wanted in my life till that time. A search for spirituality, lot of traveling and a cool life. It was pretty much the way I wished myself to morph to.</p>
<p>Talking was amazing and the view of the common junction of male and female areas (There was a complete segregation of male and female residences, kitchen and all except the meditation hall for 10 days) Yeah, pretty hard to not take a look if you find someone attractive. I talked to other few. So, it was said in email about 17 males. I haven&rsquo;t talked to them properly so I put a nickname over everyone to contemplate about these people for 10 days.</p>
<p>Let me introduce you to them:
Me, The Amazing Indian Guy, The Nepalese uncle, The Nepalese Grandfather, The Shaman Guy, The Ninja guy, The Silent Roomie, ( The last three were my roommates), The Yoga guy, The Beard Guy, The Brad Pitt Guy, The Sadistic Guy,
The Indian tech Guy, The Indian Blank Guy, The Brown Mustache Guy, The Harry Potter Guy, The FBI guy, The Yogi volunteer
I don&rsquo;t know why I put the word &ldquo;Guy&rdquo; behind everyone. So lets leave it.
Now let me explain why I named them so.
You pretty much understand a few, rest I&rsquo;ll explain. On the first day, The Shaman Guy was talking about something I didn&rsquo;t understand and in midst I hear this word Shaman and looked fancy cuz I didn&rsquo;t know what it meant.
The Ninja Guy: He was cutting bamboo and rest behind our dorms and making a stick to play with his fingers like a Ninja. I thought he was not serious in meditation at all from the very first moment.
The FBI guy: I contemplated for 10 days to uncover the secret behind the numbers pasted in his bottle. He looked gloomy at the beginning. Maybe, he is hiding right here.
The numbers were pasted by his brother and it was some kind of Japanese technique of wishing good to someone.
Oh my poor thoughts&hellip; They were into everything on a damn uncomfortable level.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t know anyone except two on this first day and now we are going to live together for 10 days without even talking with expressions.</p>
<p>Lets start the 10 days journey. You are experiencing a vivid journey of 10 days of meditation, so better take a long breath before we start.
I have one task for you. Wherever you feel like I am exaggerating something, increase the count. Let&rsquo;s see how much I can exaggerate this experience.</p>
<p>Day 1:
The time table is so strict to get up soon and start meditating all day. This is first day contemplating how shit I was to forget the soap and toothpaste. I was into it. I ate, I slept easy though. It was like easy meditation for the first day.
The meals I thought I would not survive out of it. There was no dinner and still need to wake up so early. I am quiet an early bird and I thought it was like back home:hungry when I woke up but it went quiet the opposite. The diet was actually
enough since we had no mechanical work except walk a few steps on the walking trail inside the center. But one thing was missing. We got a very good view of mountains and lake from there and it was usurped from us. Ugh&hellip; painful.
This was the best scene and they keep it restricted. It was a perfect place to meditate like the sagas of sages describes. It was the night I suffocated due to my blanket and felt horrible. I couldn&rsquo;t breathe for about a minute.
However, I felt asleep soon.</p>
<p>Day 2:
The nature was pretty amazing and from the dining seat, it was such a beautiful scenario. Today, a thorn was taken out. There came a slip in dining with a notice that if somebody wanted the supplies like soaps, toothpaste etc.
They could ask now and pay on the tenth day. A long sigh&hellip; A big relief for me. In the mornings and evenings, almost everyone was like standing on the trail looking at the last light when the day is finally going to be over.
Machhapuchre from the side and Annapurna: they were standing so peaceful. They were like soft from the inside and determined from the inside,stronger than everything. I was also worried if I get to take a good bath because the meal break
didn&rsquo;t use to be long. What if all went for the bathroom at the same time? I was worried about these little things that actually didn&rsquo;t make any difference in my life. This was the time I got to see a butterfly that I fell in love with.
It was matte black from inside and pretty oraange and yellow from outside. It had like two tails and it&rsquo;s movements were like those of a beautiful dancer on one of big stages. I tried hard to get it into my hand and see closely.
After waiting patiently for 30 minutes or so I got it. It was like achieving something great.</p>
<p>Day 3:
The meditational techniques were changing and I was trying to get my questions answered rather than the meditation itself. I would do for few moments the exercise they tell me to do then my mind would wander so fast. I was letting my mind
go wherever it wants because I thought how much thoughts could I possibly have when there&rsquo;s nothing happening new and you would pretty much contemplate everything. I had believed that in 4 or 5 days I would think so much that my over thinking thoughts would come to an end and I was just doing it. One funny thing I tried: I saw one of the guys walking bare footed. Just to look like a serious meditator, I also took off my slippers and walked around like I had attained some heavenly
Nirvana or something. Counting the end of 10 days was like: The 9th and 10th, a feeling that just one day will make everything easy. So 5 days more I was soothing myself.</p>
<p>Day 4:
This day, I looked at myself and thought I need to cut my beard off. If I cut it now, my face won&rsquo;t look like one of a child. I had tried partly on my previous year&rsquo;s vacation, so I knew it well. So, I thought to myself these people don&rsquo;t know me and also don&rsquo;t talk to me, so I will shave my beard this day. But as I said I had no razor or anything. So, I wrote for a razor on that day and waited for it to come. In the meantime, I&rsquo;d think like what would I do if they give me a Rs 5 blade and I cut my neck off. It took about 4 hours of that day&rsquo;s contemplation from time to time. It came again and again those pictures like I was cutting my throat and all. It was quiet disturbing to observe my reality from this point of time now. We were taught Vipasana this day and three hours of serious meditation as well. A lot of back pain, a lot and lot I tell you.</p>
<p>Day 5:
Now the meditation seems to be a bit deeper. Everyone seems to be more focused than they were before trying harder into it. The fear of razor was still haunting me in between. If I don&rsquo;t get a razor today I thought by the time I will be out, I will be like a kid, I feared.
Sometimes, I would get into meditation procedure quickly and be focused but sometimes it didn&rsquo;t focus at all. It was really true: I was a prisoner of my own mind. It became a lot clearer by this day.
The sedimentation and decantation of my thoughts was taking no seriousness, the thoughts do persist even now and I was amazed by the quantity. It was an endless river and I thought was never coming to an end.
Also, the body ached a lot. Everyone is doing some stretching or yoga. I am trying to copy some of them and it was fun. I think it&rsquo;s the day I saw the full moon so beautiful. There were webs all over trees and grass. The moon shining through
the thin fabric of spider&rsquo;s web, just imagine it yourself.</p>
<p>Day 6:
This day, I get a razor. Wow.. still 4 days left. Let&rsquo;s do it. They got me a good one. Fortunately,The memo of shave was short: I mean the cuts. :D Now I am a bit serious. I really felt like walking not just to be so but to feel the ground beneath me.
To feel everything that happens inside and outside me. I was looking at the mountains and they were getting more white each day, more beautiful each day. One more was a single boat in my entire view of lake. Everyone is quiet and into nature, more peaceful.</p>
<p>Day 7:
This was probably the best day I could remember. I got up at like 2. I didnt have a watch. Who keeps one on this age of cellphones, I thought. I realized I liked to have a watch now although I will have my phone when I am out.
I had a lucid dream that answered a few part of my questions I was searching for. Then, I went to meditate and focused for an hour or so. I suddenly get an amazing thought in between and was so much happy. I got out and walked around two rounds of the trail
without slippers. The cold was soothing my over-excitement of happiness and I knew I needed to be calm now as well. Now I was meditating well and suddenly I had a boner on the middle of meditation and changed my position to a comfortable one
:one like a super enjoying type. The volunteer came up to me to change the position while I think everyone was closing their eyes. I was red and shy. Oh man&hellip; I got it over in a hour. If I was out and experienced such a situation, I&rsquo;d feel like
shame for a maybe a week.</p>
<p>Day 8:
The previous day I was so much into meditation and enjoying myself as well. But starting this day was a bit difficult. I was asking myself questions and searching for answers rather than trying the meditational procedure. And in the daytime,
I glanced a volleyball match on the other side of the lake. I was looking from the spaces in between the branches of trees to get a view of what&rsquo;s on the other side. The bset part was to move here and there and create partial views to finally
understand the complete view of the other side. The moment &ldquo;The Ninja Guy&rdquo; left, one space in room made another one in my heart. I can leave as well since I have got what I was looking for. It was like some kind of loneliness and more of impatience.</p>
<p>&amp;nbsp;</p>
<p>Day 9:
This day was more like pain because three had left already and I couldn&rsquo;t concerntrate on myself. Now, The Yoga guy left. I felt he was serious towards this meditation but left. I felt kind of a despir within me. The clock was moving like a snail and my thoughts were trying to eat me back again. I was more peaceful than before but not as calm as I thought I had become.
My stomach still blurped when I thought of something I feared. The mountains and lake were quiet the motivation. Their calmness was the only helping key and later on I was meditating a bit better. One beautiful moment was my play with a butterfly with my long shadow.
I was kinda like an innocent and peaceful child. ;) The rest of the day went on with nothing special.</p>
<p>Day 10:
This day was out of my count for first 7 days. But, On the eighth, it came to be a big clock ticking like months to pass hours for last two days. But after the morning meditation, breakfast was served. That breakfast: the smell, the foods, the number of dishes on your seat Just Wow.
Everyone&rsquo;s face was sparkling so bright and smiling with themselves. I kinda glanced at someone and shared a smile because it was a big happiness considering my mind status for last two days. There were nine dishes for breakfast.
My tummy had no place for fruits. This was oh&hellip; imagine the most beautiful word you can get and fill the blanks.
It was on the 10th when I experienced something like heavenly with a particle like thing on my backbone. It was moving up and down and moves up to head and felt like a tree was growing in my brain. I was laughing with myself.
As a kid, when someone plays you to make you laugh and ask to stop, it was somehow similar. This was just a unexpected sensation and nothing more but beautiful.
Now it was the talking time at 10. As my friend had told he was like silent for a month after return but I was jolly, too eager to get enlightened by their experiences.
When we started talking, there was no stop to it. The view was mesmerizing all around, the expressions of happiness and it was certainly heavenly. Now I get to know them on a deeper level. We talked all along although we had meditation sessions in between.
So much talking&hellip; whoo. The Shaman guy was the boss of a textile industry and his story was amazing. He had meditational blocks made by Nike. Nike WTF? Yeah Nike even made these. I saw a lot of equipments used for making meditations easy, I didnt even know these existed.
Earning money and owning something was quiet different from what I thought. He wanted to get out off his own company at that time and this whole trip without asking for a leave was a sign for them to understand it, he said.
There was a guy who left an IT company he started and walked around without a thought of what he might be at his country back. During the meditation days, I felt as if he had big trouble. On this day, I came to knew all about his company but he seemed less troubled now.
I talked a lot and lot, might-be most talked to him after the Indian one. It not only was peace for him to share but for me as well. Somethings resonated to my thoughts and taught me something precious.
Their professions Biomedical Engineers, System Design at Cisco, Entrepreneurs and all. The difference between us and them is that they work a lot when they need to. I think I was the youngest of the group, so I experienced so much of life from around the world in those 10 days.
Maybe, it will take me even 40 years to travel 4 or 5 countries as per the current scenario. So, it was quiet mesmerizing.</p>
<p>The journey ended in the morning of 11th day 7 am.</p>
<p>The experience I shared is mostly the outwards experience. I cannot share in words what I truly felt from the inside. As you can Google for things like DMT trips and all, it was kind of one. I always rushed away from my thoughts, it was
the first time I just observed them. Everyone speaks of not being able to control themselves but most of us don&rsquo;t even want to give a try. A try to tame your wild bull, a try to think things from some different perspective than you
usually live in and mostly to experience something amazing everyone felt who have been to Vipasana. I have found quiet unlikely that people express this ten days meditation as a waste of time because those who experienced it are quiet
eager to speak and motivate others to go to it. It means it&rsquo;s something different. Quiet out from religious dogmas, it is quiet more like a dissection of yourself by yourself. So, in a belief that I could ask more of you to experience
the thing I experienced, to be able to hear more stories and motivate each others to continue this practise. We have a facility even free of cost which says by itself that Volunteering is the greatest donation rather than money and expects
your happiness in return for the 10 days experience, why not give it a try.
The outwards experience and learning as mine might differ from place you choose to go to meditate but the internal feelings of happiness will pretty much be same. If you like it, share it. Share your experiences as well. I will be more than happy to hear of your wonderful feelings.
Ask others to join you when you complete one. Let&rsquo;s try what we have at our own doorsteps by taking 10 days out our hectic life not for someone else but for own self. If you cannot find 10 days, go for shorter ones or simply go and have a seat in one of those. You are most likely to feel a different vibration because of the place they have set up just by volunteering. If you think I have exaggerated, I haven&rsquo;t. You can give a fair try to it in many Vipasana centers across the country. I want to thank Vipasana center, my friends during the meditation, management and everyone heartfully for providing me this amazing experience to share with you all. Thank you all for going through this long writing patiently as well.</p>
<p>May all be happy and peaceful. Bhawatu Saba Mangala.:)</p>
<h2 id="some-memories">Some Memories</h2>
<figure><img src="/ox-hugo/_20230904_110027screenshot.png"
         alt="Figure 1: Cristoph&amp;rsquo;s stone made counting device for 10 days: 10 lines"/><figcaption>
            <p><span class="figure-number">Figure 1: </span>Cristoph&rsquo;s stone made counting device for 10 days: 10 lines</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure><img src="/ox-hugo/_20230904_110152screenshot.png"
         alt="Figure 2: View I lived with for 10 days"/><figcaption>
            <p><span class="figure-number">Figure 2: </span>View I lived with for 10 days</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>caption: Group Photo 11th day
<img src="/ox-hugo/_20230904_110307screenshot.png" alt=""></p>
<figure><img src="/ox-hugo/_20230904_110358screenshot.png"
         alt="Figure 3: Cloudy view of the Mountains"/><figcaption>
            <p><span class="figure-number">Figure 3: </span>Cloudy view of the Mountains</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure><img src="/ox-hugo/_20230904_110459screenshot.png"
         alt="Figure 4: A Lonely Boat Cr: Dominique"/><figcaption>
            <p><span class="figure-number">Figure 4: </span>A Lonely Boat Cr: Dominique</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Peak Poem</title>
            <link>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/1/01/peak-poem/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/posts/1/01/peak-poem/</guid>
            <description>Peak Peak they saw, Thought they made, Of the day when their steps would be on the mountain peak, Clear seem&amp;rsquo;d they, Of the goal they desperately seek.
Guided by the river trail, Dreams flew high against the flow, The mountains of hope: deep and strong first, Now saw the wind of fear that slowly blow.
The path feels rough now, The silent howls of people&amp;rsquo;s voice he heard, Of those who got lost on that way, And of those who sought to walk away.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="peak">Peak</h2>
<p><strong>Peak</strong> they saw,
Thought they made,
Of the day when their steps would be on the mountain peak,
Clear seem&rsquo;d they, Of the goal they desperately seek.</p>
<p><strong>Guided</strong> by the river trail,
Dreams flew high against the flow,
The mountains of hope: deep and strong first,
Now saw the wind of fear that slowly blow.</p>
<p><strong>The path</strong> feels rough now,
The silent howls of people&rsquo;s voice he heard,
Of those who got lost on that way,
And of those who sought to walk away.</p>
<p><strong>His heart</strong> gets cold,
The body gets blue,
Creeping from the inside out,
Growls the wolf wishing to devour his vow.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
