<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emacs on Alok&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://dragarok.github.io/emacs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Emacs on Alok&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 13:23:08 +0545</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dragarok.github.io/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Shortcuts</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/emacs/emacs_shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 13:23:08 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/emacs/emacs_shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>Emacs Shortcuts  Spc f d &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; search for files in dired Spc : &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; main command Spc g s &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; git status Spc n n &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Capture template Spc n a &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; agenda view Vim commands  Ctrl up , down &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; go up and down in file q [a-z] &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; record a macro Shift &amp;raquo; &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; indent in code   Evil snipe:  s ch : go to ch ; same as f but more letters gc : to comment using evil gs [annotation] &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; to go to lines directly like vimium ease dii &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; delete inside indentation dik &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; delete inside plus a line above   Dired buffer shortcuts:  Dired marking and unmarking options: % and * keys Narrow subtree : ( Show git status for files : ) Diff one file to another: = Create a directory : + Up a directory : - Rename a file: R Change timestamp of file: T Copy filename: Y Open a sub-directory in same menu: I Change ownership of file: O Unmark all files: U Hardlink of file: H Goto file: J Counsel search online: K Encrypt, decrypt a file: ; Uncompress or compress : Z Copy file to : C Byte compile a file: B Change file mode: M Copy async to rsync : C-c C-r Wide dired mode: i   Org table by copying html table: C-c | Show all project TODOs: Spc p t Scroll other window : S-up Scroll other window down : S-down  Backlinks  Emacs Hugo Blogging  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Tramp</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/emacs/emacs_tramp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 13:03:24 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/emacs/emacs_tramp/</guid>
      <description>Tramp mode for sshing  Emacs Tramp tricks C-x C-f /ssh:root@ssb.willschenk.com:/etc/host This command will ssh into it and now projects can be browsed into emacs as if it were right here on my local machine. C-x C-f also need not be done since I have bound it to Spc-Spc. C-x C-f /sudo::/etc/hosts : edit file as sudo   Also has some tips for docker  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Tips</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/emacs/emacs_tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 12:52:04 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/emacs/emacs_tips/</guid>
      <description>Emacs   About org noter process to work with my papers
 Org-noter to start note taking mode Org-noter-create-skeleton to create the headings and subheadings from pdf into the note.  Org-noter-insert-note to insert a note into my pdf i        Showing inline images
(setq org-startup-with-inline-images t) Both of these options work and upper one is more flexible working with individual files.
    Some libraries to look at:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Hugo Blogging</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/emacs/emacs_hugo_blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 12:51:48 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/emacs/emacs_hugo_blogging/</guid>
      <description>ID: 0dacbf0d-550d-4db9-8e15-6ffcede1107c
Hugo blogging &amp;lt;0d/acbf0d-550d-4db9-8e15-6ffcede1107c/_20200426_045146screenshot.png&amp;gt;
Liked themes:
 Meme theme Harbor Cortex &amp;ndash;JethroKuan Hello friend ng rhazdon Beautiful Hugo   Blogging org mode Font    Font: Source Code Pro : big size : Looks amazing: Is in google fonts as well
//fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Roboto+Slab:700,300,400|Source+Code+Pro:500 //maxcdn.bootstrapcdn.com/font-awesome/4.3.0/css/font-awesome.min.css
    Normalize css : I don&amp;rsquo;t know what it does but looks pretty cool with all these stars on github.
I think I have a faint idea now about what it does.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Windows Installation</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/emacs/emacs-windows-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 12:51:30 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/emacs/emacs-windows-installation/</guid>
      <description>Problems with installing   Not having msys2 so that pdftools can&amp;rsquo;t build [install msys]
  Not having mingw so that sqlite can&amp;rsquo;t build for org-roam [choco install mingw] Don&amp;rsquo;t even have to do that. The mingw is installed by msys2. So go to mysys2: there will be folder named mingw64. Add it&amp;rsquo;s bin to the PATH.
pacman -Syu pacman -S base-devel pacman -S mingw-w64-x86_64-toolchain pacman -S mingw-w64-x86_64-zlib pacman -S mingw-w64-x86_64-libpng pacman -S mingw-w64-x86_64-poppler pacman -S mingw-w64-x86_64-imagemagick   Then find a version that supports modules : emax64.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Completion</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/emacs/emacs-completion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 12:51:16 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/emacs/emacs-completion/</guid>
      <description>Vim&amp;rsquo;s omni like completion Keybind	Description C-x C-]	Complete etags C-x C-f	Complete file path C-x C-k	Complete from dictionary/keyword C-x C-l	Complete full line C-x C-o	Invoke complete-at-point function C-x C-n	Complete next symbol at point C-x C-p	Complete previous symbol at point C-x C-s	Complete snippet C-x s	Complete spelling suggestions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Setup</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/emacs/emacs_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/emacs/emacs_setup/</guid>
      <description>Python installs sudo pip install pipenv sudo pip install pytest sudo pip install nose sudo pip install black sudo pip install pyflakes sudo pip install poetry sudo pip install isort sudo pip install &amp;#39;python-language-server[all]&amp;#39; Go setup sudo pacman --needed --noconfirm -S go go get -u github.com/motemen/gore go get -u github.com/nsf/gocode go get -u golang.org/x/tools/cmd/godoc go get -u golang.org/x/tools/cmd/goimports go get -u golang.org/x/tools/cmd/gorename go get -u golang.org/x/tools/cmd/guru Markdown setup sudo pip install grip Search Ripgrep sudo pacman --needed --noconfirm -S ripgrep sudo pacman -S fd Language tool and aspell sudo pacman -S languagetool sudo pacman -S aspell aspell-en Web npm install -g js-beautify Shell sudo pacman -S shellcheck npm i -g bash-language-server Rust rustup update rustup component add rls rust-analysis rust-src rustup component add rustfmt-preview cargo install cargo-check rustup component add clippy-preview Org mode sudo pacman -S flameshot sudo pacman -S gnuplot sudo pacman -S texlive-core texlive-bin texlive-science sudo pacman -S pandoc sudo pacman -S hugo C/C++ sudo pacman -S clang cmake Delta [ git-delta ] cargo install git-delta Add this to your ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>