<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Neurosciences on </title>
    <link>https://dragarok.github.io/neuroscience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Neurosciences on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0545</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dragarok.github.io/neuroscience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FMRI Hyperalignment</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/neuroscience/fmri_hyperalignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/neuroscience/fmri_hyperalignment/</guid>
      <description>There is a trajectory in VTC compared to a person&amp;rsquo;s visual experience when they see different objects around in one trajectory. But relating trajectory in one region of the brain to another in voxel space is not easy since it can be very different and non-linearly following as well. But the voxel trajectory for different persons should be same. Sounds interesting but comes with a problem. How to know which voxels are same for different persons?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FMRI Comparisons and Problems</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/neuroscience/fmri_comparisons/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/neuroscience/fmri_comparisons/</guid>
      <description>If only the probability that Null Hypothesis is less than 1/20, the experiment is of scientific interest. If we treat each voxel as independent test of the hypothesis, there will be sure chances to see some example that follows null hypothesis. If there are 20 independent experiments, then the probability of finding a false positive is 0.64 For 200, it&amp;rsquo;s 0.99. Now if we are taking 20k voxels each treated as independent experiments, we are surely to find some voxels that will pass as null hypothesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Representational Similarity Analysis</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/neuroscience/representational_similarity_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/neuroscience/representational_similarity_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Question with asking how different or similar are three or more conditions to each other? Then we have a similarity matrix. For each new example, how similar are the new examples to the old examples of all classes can be asked. We can measure distance to the clouds of other classes to understand the similarity that we observe. We can have information in non-diagonal cells of similarity matrix to understand more interesting information about relation between these classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FMRI bootcamp</title>
      <link>https://dragarok.github.io/neuroscience/fmri_bootcamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragarok.github.io/neuroscience/fmri_bootcamp/</guid>
      <description>Different views of the brain Coronal view: View after cutting the face off. Sagittal medial view: Cutting brain from the sides into the middle. Lateral Sagittal view: Take the skull off. Axial view: Look from the top after cutting off a piece. Sulca: Bottom of cortical folds Gyrus: Top of cortical folds Different Imaging Techniques Anatomical Imaging Axial slices are 2D representations. Making multiple axial slices &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; 3D representation of the brain Slices can be separated by some space.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
